<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="rss.css" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Latest from Luke</title><description>Updates from Luke Smith. Throw this in your RSS feeder for instant updates!</description><language>en-us</language><link>https://lukesmith.xyz/rss.xml</link><atom:link href="https://lukesmith.xyz/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><image><title>The Latest from Luke</title><url>https://lukesmith.xyz/pix/luke.gif</url><link>https://lukesmith.xyz/rss.xml</link></image><!-- LB --><item><title>Break week</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#break-week</guid><pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 00:24:22 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>I've been taking a week off from some things, including <a href="http://notrelated.xyz">Not Related!</a> to do some reading and research and maybe even bulk up. I'll have a new episode of the podcast (mostly planned out) out next week and I think I'll do a screencast over the weekend.</p><p>You may've noticed I haven't done a livestream in a while, but I'm thinking to start again.I'm not entirely sure how my internet up connection is here, but I might be doing a stream next Tuesday or Wednesday around midday around Amerimutt time.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Any Paleo-Anthropologists or geneticists reading? On the Toba Population Bottleneck</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#any-paleoanthropologists-or-geneticists-reading-on-the-toba-population-bottleneck</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 12:20:15 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>There's an often repeated idea out there that humans went through a population bottleneck about 70,000 years ago, shrinking to a group of only several thousands. This bottleneck is typically attributed to the Toba Eruption.This is something you've probably heard <em>ad nauseam</em> in every popular science depiction of human prehistory, I sure have.I won't give specifics because I don't want to bias you, but in doing research for a future podcast episode, I began to doubt this idea and tried to pry into its actual origins to see what the actual evidence of it was.</p><p>I was surprised to learn that the idea didn't actually come from some scholarly consensus, but is a still very controversial idea originally posited by a journalist Ann Gibbons of <i>Science</i>.Now anyone who knows me knows that I am the absolutely last to write off an idea or theory because it's posited by a lay(wo)man out of the academic system, but in the case of a <em>journalist</em> (that class of people whose ratios of what-they-know to what-they-think-they-know are extremely low), my initial doubt feels a little vindicated.</p><p>I've been groping through some scientific literature on the subject, there are indeed some mainstream supporters, but from what I can tell, the evidence for it is very scant, at least far too scant to warrant its commonplace presentation in popular science.As well, it seems that a lot of people in other fields base some of their assumptions on this idea, not knowing its non-universality, thus giving their theories a shaky foundation.</p><p>I bring this up because I'm curious if anyone reading has had specific, semi-direct knowledge or experience with the feeling in the field.As I said, I'm gradually reading the literature on it already, but I'm curious to know an insider's view (or at least the view of someone well-informed on it).Is this idea well-accepted?Is the circumstantial evidence for it considered up to snuff?Are there good reasons to think it's <em>not</em> true?Email me what you think.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Democracy: The Rule of NPCs</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#democracy-the-rule-of-npcs</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 19:15:47 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p><a target="_blank" href="http://notrelated.libsyn.com/democracy-rule-of-the-npcs">New episode of Not Related!</a> out. Entitled "Democracy: Rule of the NPCs". Link to the RSS feed: <a target="_blank" href="https://notrelated.libsyn.com/rss">https://notrelated.libsyn.com/rss</a>.</p><p>In addition to talking about Schumpeter's previously mentioned book, we also talk about Bryan Caplan's <em>The Myth of the Rational Voter</em> and James Burnham's <em>The Machiavellians: The Defenders of Freedom</em>.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>R.I.P. Lincucks! Some comments on recent events</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#rip-lincucks-some-comments-on-recent-events</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 21:24:14 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pwn3gIipCjU">A video on the recent Linux code of conduct controversy.</a></p><p>Next episode of <em>Not Related!</em> will be recorded tomorrow.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Yes, I'm doing a video on it...</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#yes-im-doing-a-video-on-it</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 13:59:23 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>I've been getting non-stop emails about the Linux Code of Conduct thing and Linus leaving the project. A video on it is uploading (will take a while, many GB).</p>]]></description></item><item><title>SSL cert failures with Gmail accounts (mutt-wizard)</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#ssl-cert-failures-with-gmail-accounts-muttwizard</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 13:41:55 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>This actually isn't a mutt-wizard-specific problem, but I've been getting a lot of questions about it since mutt-wizard relies on offlineimap and ergo OpenSSL. Long story short, if you have updated Arch Linux recently, your new version of offlineimap/OpenSSL might give you a certificate error when attempting to sync with a Gmail account.</p><p>To solve this, do one of the following:</p><ul>	<li>Downgrade to an earlier version of offlineimap/OpenSSL</li>	<li>Add <code>ssl_version=tls1_2</code> to the remote Gmail repository in <code>~/.offlineimaprc</code>.</li>	<li>Sit and wait for a fix.</li>	<li>Stop using Gmail :varg: (my favorite ;-))</li></ul><p>See the <a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/LukeSmithxyz/mutt-wizard/issues/85">Github Issue</a> that GrimKriegor opened on the mutt-wizard repo about this, with links to the relevant sources.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Le Purity-Spiral Nationalism</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#le-purityspiral-nationalism</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 01:23:12 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p><a target="_blank" href="http://notrelated.xyz/albions-seed-and-an-ethnic-history-of-america">New episode of Not Related!</a> out on <em>Albion's Seed: Four British Folkways in America</em>.</p><p>The general argument of the book is that America, as it exists ethno-culturally has never been one unit, but four loosely competitive and highly distinct cultures, directly rooted in particular British origins.On the surface this book is a dense and well-researched ethnography, but deeper than that, it has a lot of hot take-aways for American socio-political life.It was a fascination back when it was published, but as people are beginning to be more real about the position of racial and cultural identity in politics, it's a book and argument that you're starting to here about more and more.</p><p>I say so a couple times in the podcast, but this is a book far more expansive than what I can sum up in a measly 90 minutes for you, so if the podcast piques your interest, check the book out yourself! You'll get a good mind for it in the episode, but this is one of those books that transcends one simple thesis statement in scope.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>THICC podcast episode coming</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#thicc-podcast-episode-coming</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 23:35:35 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>I've been unofficially aiming to release a <em>Not Related</em> episode every week at the end of week, but the THICC book I'm covering this time required a lot of prep, and it's not out yet as you can see! It will be out tomorrow.</p><p>I've already recorded <em>an hour and twenty minutes</em>, which requires a lot of stopping and rerecording and audio fixes.As I'm still acclimating to recording this takes a lot of time, but as I improve my process, I'm hoping to record episodes in one run without splicing necessary.</p><p>Anyway, just saying this because I haven't forgotten about it and I've been working a lot. I'll have yet another episode out later in the week.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Terry Davis has died.</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#terry-davis-has-died</guid><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 09:51:50 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>You may have heard already, but it appears that Terry Davis is confirmed to have died last month in what seems to have been a suicide. I just put up a brief video on this <a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Bs_fEkU8Qco">here</a>.</p><p>You can still go to his site at <a target="_blank" href="http://templeos.org">TempleOS.org</a> which has the downloads to Temple OS and a brief update after his death.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>We need to start studying NPCs scientifically</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#we-need-to-start-studying-npcs-scientifically</guid><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 19:39:44 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>The talk of the meme-o-sphere recently has been on NPCs (non-player characters), not in video games, but in real life.Originally, "NPC" arose as a term of abuse approximating "normie" or "brainlet", but there have been some who are realizing that it might have more truth to it than anticipated.</p><p>For a while now, a <a target="_blank" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/self/comments/3yrw2i/i_never_thought_with_language_until_now_this_is/">post from le Reddit</a> has been circulating from a somewhat disturbed user divulged that he only recently began thinking in language, saying that his life before "mindless" and "soul-less" and described himself as "barely even conscious".One might also be reminded of the quip of James Huneker on Chopin's &Eacute;tude Op. 25, Num. 11 (better known nowadays by being quoted by Douglass Hofstadter in G&ouml;del, Escher, Bach) that "small-souled men, no matter how agile their fingers, should avoid it".Of course, listeners of the biggest-braned podcast <a target="_blank" href="http://notrelated.xyz">Not Related!</a> will remember in <a target="_blank" href="http://notrelated.xyz/the-origin-of-consciousness-in-the-breakdown-of-the-bicameral-mind">the episode on the Bicameral Mind</a>, we talked on Julian Jaynes's theory of consciousness, in which consciousness is not something inherent to our biological inventory, but a kind of mental habit we develop, partially based on the metaphors of language and our need in society.Different societies and cultures are liable to create different levels of consciousness in people.</p><p>There seems to be circumstantial evidence everywhere that the internal worlds of others just are not quite the same as ours.There's a huge scientific and epistemological problem though: how can we empirically and objectively verify the nature consciousness, an aspect of mental life which is by its nature accessible only subjectively?</p><p>I dont think this question is answerable in the scientific mindset we currently have.More interesting as a hint would be a deeper understanding, albeit indirect of what other people's inner worlds are like.I'm sort of curious to hear what <b>your</b> inner life is like, and how you experience "thinking" if it's something unique.</p><p>I'll do my part and share with others my mental life.I do have internal speech and am not an NPC and am indeed conscious.My internal speech is a little bit different from how I hear others describe theirs.Sometimes, usually when I'm thinking very slowly and deliberately, I think at only slightly faster than enunciated English in real life.Most of the time, the "speech" is quite different: the best way I can describe the experience is as if you "hummed" the intonation of English to yourself without opening your mouth (this is not something I literally do, but how I experience it in my head). This mild humming occurs at a speed significantly faster than normal speech and though it provokes the same "meaning" and cognitive scaffolding as language does. It's not an annoying or abrasive humming, I should say: it's more like if someone is gently (though quickly) talking in the other room.This hummed speech "feels" like English, but when I slow it down because it just gave me a great idea that I want to write down, I realize that there sometimes aren't actually English words or English syntax that directly capture what I was thinking.</p><p>I should say, when I say that it "feels" like English, I mean that, as someone who knows a lot of different languages and has an intuitive grasp of etymology, I have distinct, almost synesthetic feelings that correspond to words of different origins. When I experience what linguists call "tip of the tongue phenomena" (when you forgot a word but can remember what it means and how it starts), I also can recall the approximate etymology. What I mean is that this humming speech has the same feeling as English words do.</p><p>I'd probably say that most of my mental time does <em>not</em> use this kind of internal speech.It's not that I'm unconscious, but because I usually think about more abstract and non-linear things with interlocking, organic shapes.This is a little closer to how some savants describe their mental life, but I suspect it's a lot more common than that, not just because I have it, but it seems to be the kind of thing that people would take for granted.The typical description is that invisible shapes of different "meanings" come together and connect, or hydraulic organic machinery interacts in such a way to give you the correct answers to math problems or some advanced mental decision whose actual mechanism is opaque to you.The thing is, while I experience this, it's something I'm only an observer of, and while I say that the shapes have "meanings", that's sort of my assumption, because if you could display my cognitive theater on a screen, I couldn't point out what is what with my conscious mind.I think this is some kind of felt vision into the structure of intuition more than anything else.</p><p>As a minor detail, I also have no cognitive "me". Or at least not unless I want one.What I mean by that is that people will often describe themselves in their imaginations as seeing in the first person, or seeing themselves in third person (as if watching themselves on TV).These are sometimes called the "I" and "me".I can easily imagine myself, say, taking a walk and seeing myself walking from above, but that's not something I regularly do without prodding.Whenever I imagine myself doing something, I see everything from my own eyes unless deliberately trying to do otherwise.</p><p>Anyway, in the future, as I read more of the literature, I might be interested in doing an episode on "NPC" and people's inner lifes.If you have a mental life that is notable or distinct, feel free to email me a brief explanation. I'm curious to see what's out there.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Alex Jones, increasingly BASED, now even more banned from everything</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#alex-jones-increasingly-based-now-even-more-banned-from-everything</guid><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 19:34:15 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>Well-known and loved water-filter merchant Alex Jones was banned from Twitter, in a move that shocked no one.After a sustained campaign of harassment from Bluechecks, Twitter finally gave in and banned him and his site <a target="_blank" href="https://infowars.com">InfoWars.com</a>, thus depriving Twitter of Super Male Vitality and other high-energy supplements.</p><p>Thankfully, the straw that broke the camel's back was absolutely based.The rationalization for the ban was the fact that yesterday Alex posted videos haranguing a CNN journalist who had worked tirelessly to get him and others banned and deplatformed.The journalist was shook to say the least, visibly timid and obviously wishing he was a turtle so he could retract his head into his shell.After several minutes of straight roasting (peppered with some attempted "comebacks" from the journo), Chuck Johnson (the guy noted for being banned from Twitter back when no one got banned) joined in as well, the video later ending with a close up of the journalist's eyes, tearing up and silently distraught.</p><p>Journo-bugmen and pseudo-intellects in universities have been subjecting Americans to a non-stop humiliation-fest and struggle session since at least the 1960s.These people are literally paid by corporations and government organizations to demean, destroy and "deconstruct" the lives of the people that pay their bills.They circulate baseless folklore and conspiracy theories about non-bugmen.They live obliviously and smugly sit and design what they want the world of others to look like.They talk tough and snidely on news stations and in university, but as soon as you shine the light on them, they curl up in shame.Their pretenses only exist in their isolated world where they can't be debated, made fun of, humiliated or held accountable.They're also just dumb.</p><p>Alex's unpardonable sin is subjecting one of these chosen beings, one of these Excelsites to mockery.Alex deserves a lot of credit for making this joker tear up.Hopefully you're going to see a lot more of it too from more people.If rational debate worked, Someone like Charles Murray would've won it for us decades ago. It doesn't, and now everyone hates Charles Murray. Even people on the real right.The real solution is Chad Nationalism, Day of the Swirly, all that.Buglibs are not serious people. Don't take them seriously. Bugmen only exist because we allow that psychological type to fester.One might want to reread Uncle Ted's section on "the Psychology of Modern Leftism" as a reminder.</p><p>As it comes to Infowars, of course, using platforms and social media is for brainlets anyways. Big-branes always subscribe directly to RSS feeds. Here are Infowars'; slap them in your RSS feed reader:</p><ul><li><a target="_blank" href="https://www.infowars.com/feed/custom_feed_rss">https://www.infowars.com/feed/custom_feed_rss</a> (Articles)</li><li><a target="_blank" href="http://xml.nfowars.net/Alex.rss">http://xml.nfowars.net/Alex.rss</a> (Alex Jones's show)</li></ul><p>I'm too woke for Infowars myself, but when they were originally banned from YouTube and everything else, the first thing I did was put these feeds into newsboat in raw solidarity. I'll read an article or two that sound funny and not too Boomer-con. Of course I mean no disrespect to Alex's highly esoteric (essentially Gnostic) understanding of the elite's cosmology and eschatology, which is actually unironically spot on.</p><p>The greatest part is that for the shitlib hivemind, it's just not enough!Bugman brainlets are not scREEEsching about Alex being even allowed on the site in the first place.</p><p>By the way, <b>stop using Twitter!</b>Twitter, more than any other social media company is on the verge of financial ruin. Do your part and don't use the site unless via RSS feeds.There are a couple of okay people on Twitter, but most everyone worth following has left or been banned a long time ago.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>NotRelated.xyz Website is now up!</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#notrelatedxyz-website-is-now-up</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 12:08:58 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>The podcast now has its own domain at <a target="_blank" href="http://notrelated.xyz">notrelated.xyz</a>, which is a bit easier to remember than the libsyn subdomain for those who aren't familiar with libsyn.</p><p>For people who care, <a target="_blank" href="http://notrelated.xyz">notrelated.xyz</a> does <em>not</em> have SSL/https and I probably won't set it up because, frankly, I don't see it as necessary (I mean I have it for my main domain, but I don't even see <em>that</em> as very necessary). If I change my mind on this, I'll tell you.Of course if you just have to have SSL/https, you can still use the libsyn address to access either the podcast webpage at <a target="_blank" href="https://notrelated.libsyn.com">https://notrelated.libsyn.com</a> or the RSS feed at <a target="_blank" href="https://notrelated.libsyn.com/rss">https://notrelated.libsyn.com/rss</a>.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>You can now donate Bitcoin!</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#you-can-now-donate-bitcoin</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 11:17:21 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>I've finally taken the basic step of setting up a Bitcoin wallet, etc. after many requests from users.So you can donate Bitcoin using the address below:</p><p>1FhhM4KgEzKizGsDRyT49JANYwqMU6AeKx</p><p>You can go to my <a href="https://lukesmith.xyz/bitcoin.html">Bitcoin page</a> to see a QR code for it if you want.</p><p>If you want to donate "publicly" to be read out on the podcast, just send me a notification email with your name, comment and the donation amount for confirmation.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>My diet following the memes</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#my-diet-following-the-memes</guid><pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 23:44:33 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>Abiding by an ideological "diet" is pure autism. It's peak dystopian, actually. Identifying with some meme diet you've become rationally convinced of is like identifying by the music you listen to or some autistically-differentiated political label. It's something people only do in a bugman society when they've been deprived of their real identity.</p><p>Nonetheless, I occasionally get questions about what I eat and as I go on, my functional diet changes, but interesting patterns emerge.Nowadays you've had meme diets from Atkins to Paleo to this new keto meme; all of them circulate around the idea that the food pyramid is a lie, and meats and fats are severely underrated.In my experience, I'm very inclined to agree.In fact, one of the realities of nutrition "science" is that a lot of the jack-booting, tone-setting and "advocacy" has always been done by either Jehovah's Witnesses or vegetarians, two parties who have ideological motivations to downplay the good of meat and to overplay the good of "slave foods" like cereals and starchy staples.I'm not bothered by their ethical pretenses, but it's a whole nother thing to pretend that they're based in the reality of what's good for humans aside from pietisms.</p><p>First, for my younger viewers, you'll realize as you get "old" (as you leave puberty at least around 25), your digestive abilities and metabolism change.The young digestive system is much more plastic and durable than someone in the late 20s and on. You've probably heard that you'll put on weight more easier if you eat pizza, true for most people, but for me, I've found that it's increasingly difficult even to properly <em>digest</em> greasy pizza, junk food, sugars and everything processed and terrible about the modern world.As you get a little older, you really can <em>feel</em> the debilitatingly negative hormonal effects of carbo-loading. You get acid-reflux and indigestion more too. Domino's is a one-way ticket to diarrhea.Hell, a couple weeks ago in a silly attempt to put on empty weight, I bought and ate a meek-and-mild <em>Cheerios</em> knock-off and let's just say that came out looking about the same as they went in.</p><p>Don't worry, I'm not falling apart. The solution has been easy.Stop eating processed foods. Stop eating sugar. And Stop eating the Virgin Bottom-of-the-Food-Pyramid. Just eat meat.</p><p>I don't eat <em>only</em> meat now, but I abandoned the pretense and can acknowledge that meals are nothing more than a serving of meat with some other mostly decorative foods.I have some vegetables and fruits here and there, and I do go out to eat and get a sandwich (with bread of course) every once in a while.I'll say that I've realized that I can detect a little digestive difference between meat treated with antibiotics and that without. Might be confirmation bias, but I prefer untreated or organic meat and will buy it if it's not too much more expensive. Typical meals include:</p><ul><li>Chicken thighs/legs covered in garlic powder, garlic salt, thyme and rosemary. 20 minutes on oiled tray in a 425F oven.</li><li>Steak. Rare, duh. Cooked on the range with an entire diced onion (which becomes caramelized) and about a third of a green pepper. Occasionally topped with cheese that I grate (yup, I use cheese blocks because I'm an artiste)</li><li>Whole chicken, decorated internally and externally with shards of onions, garlic and sometimes potatoes. Washed with egg white. Thyme, rosemary. Covered with foil and ovened for maybe 40 minutes.</li></ul><p>Oh and I use olive oil for all of these. None of that Cucknola oil BS. I'm also not big on salt.</p><p>And by the way, stop believing Nutrition Facts autism.The reality of nutrition "science" is that the body is a machine far more complex than we understand.The idea that our body needs precisely that 100% of all of those substances that the American government proclaimed back in the 70s is ridiculous.For the same reason, sorry, but eating something with another random protein (like le soy) isn't a substitute for the actual nourishment of meat. My scientific proof is the diminished physical and hormonal state of vegans.Some people will tell them they need B12 or something else, but it's far beyond that.Regardless "diet" foods/sodas are the same. They only exist so they look good on the nutrition facts. They produce equivalent tastes and fill your stomach with things that you're body can't digest and turn into calories/energy. In a sane society, that would be identified as being something way worse than the thing they're supposed to be replacing.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Capitalism, Socialism and Democracy UP</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#capitalism-socialism-and-democracy-up</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 23:18:55 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>New episode of the podcat out: check out <a target="_blank" href="notrelated">the website</a> and subscribe to the <a target="_blank" href="nrrss">the RSS feed</a> if you haven't already.</p><p>This episode is on Joseph Schumpeter's classic book <em>Capitalism, Socialism and Democracy</em>. I cover about 4/5ths of the books content, all of it expect Schumpeter's takes on democracy, but that part I'm thinking to include in an episode on democracy generally (along with yet another biggeder-braned and more recent book on democracy (don't ask which, you'll find out)) either later this week or next week!</p><p>I give two potential time slots because there's another book which, due to recent events in the e-celeb world, I want to cover and get out there ASAP (not tellin' which yet!). But this book itself is a sizeable tome of 900 or so pages, which I've of course read before, but want to reread for good prep! The order in which I finish prep for one or the other episode will determine to order of release ;-)</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Cell Phones and the Bronze Age Collapse (1177 BC)</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#cell-phones-and-the-bronze-age-collapse-1177-bc</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 15:24:45 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>First off, I put up a brief video talking about <a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1Fv7hN5q1N0">why I don't like using cell phones</a>, it seems it's already gotten some good feedback, so check it out if you haven't already. Cell phones are devices that encourage a kind of superficiality of mind and habit, and are not nearly as useful as we think they are. Having a truly free-as=in-freedom and privacy-respecting cell phone is, by large part, impossible.</p><p>There's also been a lot of great feedback on the first episode of <a target="_blank" href="https://lukesmith.xyz/notrelated">,Not Related</a>, which I'll go over in the next episode. I've got my prep mostly ready, I don't want to divulge the exact topic, yet. I think I'll let each episode be a surprise. I've also bought <a target="_blank" href="http://notrelated.xyz">NotRelated.xyz</a>, but as of now it will just direct to my own homepage.</p><p>By the way, since the first podcast, there was a book I mentioned in passing, Eric Cline's <em>1177 B.C.: The year Civilization Collapsed</em>. It popped in my head while recording, so I mentioned it, because I had heard very good things about it, but I decided it'd be a little hypocritical to even name-drop it without reading it ;-), so in the time since the episode, I got and read through in full and a half.</p><p>I'll say it's definitely good and worth reading. A little repetitive, but in a way that facilitates retention. If you're interesting in the period or want to get a wider view of it after the <a target="_blank" href="http://notrelated.libsyn.com/website/the-origin-of-consciousness-in-the-breakdown-of-the-bicameral-mind">Bicameral Mind</a> episode, it might be a good starting point for a historical view. There's an audiobook of it floating out there too.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>The Real Bronze-Age Mindset!</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#the-real-bronze-age-mindset</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 22:54:49 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>Be sure to subscribe to the podcast RSS feed: <a target="_blank" href="http://notrelated.libsyn.com/rss">http://notrelated.libsyn.com</a> and you can check out the automatic blog <a target="_blank" href="http://notrelated.libsyn.com">here</a>. I'll be posting podcast updates on my personal RSS feed regardless just for completeness sake, but will gradually keep them to their own magisterium.</p><p>The newest podcast episode (direct link <a target="_blank" href="http://traffic.libsyn.com/notrelated/S01E01_-_The_Origin_of_Consciousness_in_the_Breakdown_of_the_Bicameral_Mind.mp3">here</a>) is on the <em>true</em> Bronze-Age Mindset, well, sort of. It's on <b>Julian Jaynes</b>' theory of the <b>"Origin of Consciousness in the Breakdown of the Bicameral Mind"</b>, which amounts to arguing that humans before the Bronze Age Collapse were, in fact, not conscious among many other wild, yet surprisingly justifiable things.</p><p>I'll also have a YT video equivalent of the podcast, which will be available tomorrow morning at <a target="_blank" href="https://youtu.be/lgnMyF-o0sQ">https://youtu.be/lgnMyF-o0sQ</a>.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Full MSMTPRC support added to Mutt Wizard</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#full-msmtprc-support-added-to-mutt-wizard</guid><pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 14:48:04 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>After a recent commit, <a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/LukeSmithxyz/mutt-wizard">mutt-wizard</a> will now also generate an msmtprc file based on your settings. While mutt-wizard has had partial, expandable msmtp compatibility, it now all comes by default. This will increase some compatibility with some accounts and will give you more options in sending mail if you want to set personal msmtp settings. Remember to install the relevant msmtp package on your distro before sending mail!</p><p>Obviously the wizard will safely store your password and decrypt it only when necessary, just like with offlineimap.If you want msmtp compatibility but you've already run mutt-wizard, I recommend removing your old accounts in the dialog menu and readding them (this <em>won't</em> delete you offline email so you won't have to redownload it so long as you keep the email's account name the same).I encourage you to try it, partially because if there are errors, I'd like to find out soon! ;-)</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Mfw soydevs would use PHP for this</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#mfw-soydevs-would-use-php-for-this</guid><pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 22:36:38 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>If you check my website regularly, you may've noticed that I added a "Recent blog entries" subheading on the main page. Each time I add a new blog entry, it'll be updated to show only the most recent five. I was asked how I do this, given that my site is static, but honestly it's the easiest thing in the world, but I'll give you a hint in case it isn't obvious.</p><p>As background, I edit my website by keeping a mirror offline on my computer, then I use rsync commands (via scripts or bash aliases) to either update individually changed files, or all files. The script that updates all files also checks for other things. For example, if my CV which is in another folder has been updated, it will copy the new udpate to the website directory before uploading everything.</p><p>The "Recent blog entries" part is also handled by this "update all script". Using a <code>grep</code> command, I search my blog list file for the first five blog headers, which will be the most recent entries, and I change the formatting into a list (which is actually a single line of HTML for ease) with a <code>sed</code> command. Then, with <code>sed</code> again, I search for the previously created line, delete it and replace it with the new five entries.</p><p>As for the specific commands, you can figure them out yourself ;-). Point is, a lot of people have this domain-dependent thinking when approaching web-based file management as if core utils are unusable and we have to rely on server-side scripts even to do basic things. This is a bad mindset that causes incalculable harm on the web. Obviously core utils aren't going to get you true dynamically generated sites, but you can get most use cases out of plain HTML and should try to do so whenever possible.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Intro podcast episode up and RSS feed available.</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#intro-podcast-episode-up-and-rss-feed-available.</guid><pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 22:14:52 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>i've put out a preliminary episode for the podcast, you can go ahead and subscribe to the RSS feed at <a target="_blank" href="http://notrelated.libsyn.com/rss">http://notrelated.libsyn.com/rss</a>.</p><p>I'll also be mirroring the episodes on YouTube and the first one is out <a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=j4fR8BQUYsQ">here</a>. Obviously I suggest using the RSS feed though just because I've gone through all the trouble of setting up a system to logically tag all the files for all you autistes who just have to have it that way ;-).</p><p>I'm using Libsyn to syndicate my podcasts as you can see by the links. I have a very high opinion of libsyn, especially compared to other platforms like YouTube, as libsyn has a relatively unblemished record of non-censorship. It will cost me money to upload on it monthly, so if you enjoy the show, please feel free to donate or the money will have to come out of my pocket.</p><p>If you have a good sense of what I'm shooting for in this podcast and have recommendation of your own, feel free to say so! As I say in this 0th episode, I plan on answering emails in the middle of the show and reading PayPal donations.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>I've deleted my Twitter</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#ive-deleted-my-twitter</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 11:53:04 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>I've deleted my Twitter. Even when I had originally joined the site, it was considerably past its prime, mainly due to its voluntary amputation of all accounts worth following,  but it's now become intolerable to even browse.The site is now a wasteland ravaged by the Eternal Bluecheck, that self-gaslighting conspiracy theorist constantly amped up by the Boomer left media and on the prowl for pearls to clutch and evens to can't.An engineered monster, now laying waste to their allotted space.</p><p>This could be fun for trolls, which I'm not anyway, but even trolling these untouchable elites is now "hate speech" and thus immediately banable.There's an esoteric insurgency on Twitter, as esotericism is the only possible cloak to protect against the now routine purges, but it's not enough for me to continue on the site which is utterly useless.Twitter is simply a dead site run by jesters in suits and there's no reason to even stave off its collapse by getting them any hits.I encourage every one else to delete their account if, for some reason, you're still on it. You can use <a target="_blank" href="https://twitrss.me">twitrss.me</a> to get an RSS feed for a Twitter account you want to follow it and get its updates in newsboat or your own RSS reader. This is actually always how I've "followed" accounts so Twitter doesn't know who I'm actually following.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Minor blog addition</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#minor-blog-addition</guid><pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 19:28:10 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>As an experiment, I've added to my blog system (<a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/LukeSmithxyz/lb">lb</a>) an extra element, only amounting to a small edition of code. This is an additional (more traditional) blog index page, which you can see <a target="_blank" href="https://lukesmith.xyz/blogindex.html">here</a>.</p><p>It's pretty simple and really just prepends new entries to the top just like the rest of the blog system does for your RSS feed and the <a href="blog.html">rolling blog file</a>. The titling by month is not automatic, so each month, you'd have to add a new heading though. Not sure if I want to bother automating that.</p><p>It does add the date to the title as well, which is automatic, but I didn't add it to older entries since I revising that would be a little more difficult.</p><p>I've pushed these changes to the Github, but they're still liable to change a little bit. You can feel free to update your local repo or not, as it won't affect the rest of the system whether you use this feature or not.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Podcast series to begin shortly</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#podcast-series-to-begin-shortly</guid><pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 19:15:29 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>I've been contemplating for a while to do a podcast series, partially at the desires of viewers and I think it's now going to happen. The general format is going to be on weekly topics, at the beginning focusing on particular books of political, scientific or other note. I originally was searching around for a co-host, but honestly couldn't find anyone I particularly liked for the job. I'm open to one in the future, but I think I'm setting myself on a detailed monologue format for now.</p><p>I've gotten specific requests for books and topics, but it's going to follow only my own instincts in the beginning, focusing mostly on unsung but potent works. The first week, I've pretty much settled on Julian Haynes' <em>The Origin of Consciousness in the Breakdown of the Bicameral Mind</em> followed by (in no particular order) Schumpeter's <em>Capitalism, Socialism and Democracy</em>, Feyerabend's <em>Against Method</em>, Hutton's <em>Race and the Third Reich</em> and Nassim Taleb's growing corpus, typically called <em>Incerto</em>.</p><p>I'm also open to having non-book based topics or perhaps talking about fiction works. Say, the works of Lovecraft or Dick or Borgres.Now this isn't supposed to be a bookclub, or a learning experience for me though. I want to focus on works and topics I've been familiar with for years, otherwise it would be pretty silly to put out content.It would sort of like those people who do "distro" reviews after playing around on a Linux distro for 10 minutes.</p><p>Anyway, I'm still divided on what to call the podcast, but I might just call it <em>No Relation</em> as a joke and allusion to the now famous <a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8SPD35ETwuk">one episode podcast my roomate and I did</a> last year, and considering it has <em>No Relation</em> to the original.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Now THIS is Bash AUTISM!</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#now-this-is-bash-autism</guid><pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 19:50:12 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p><a target="_blank" href="https://youtu.be/LbSBVf46lG0">A new brief video</a> and follow-up to the last video. I correctly prophesied that there were more decent optimizations to the script from <a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bkgeFi4PwOg">the last video</a>. Specifically, I briefly talk about <code>tee</code>, a UNIX utility which is lesser-used, but allows us to take an input and output it to multiple places, potentially performing further modifications on each of the separate streams. We save DOZENS of milliseconds in our unrelenting autismal quest for efficiency.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Don't be a Bash BRAINLET!</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#dont-be-a-bash-brainlet</guid><pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 13:08:53 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>In a <a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bkgeFi4PwOg">new vid</a>, I talk about the importance of good design, and what that means in your typical shell script. I take the example of the <a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/LukeSmithxyz/voidrice/blob/master/.scripts/shortcuts.sh">shortcut-sync script</a> I use to keep my bash, ranger and qutebrowser aliases synced and autogenerated. Originally when I wrote it, it was terribly designed, looping through a file and outputting to files six different times per line, adding up for a staggeringly long 1.5 second runtime for a 45 line script! The newer, better version (see the above link to Github), uses streams in the proper way to produce nearly instantaneous completion.</p><p>It's a pretty good example of how good (or bad) design principles can add up hugely on a system. It's almost mind-boggling to think about the difference that well-written and efficient code can make even for typical users as you add up the hundres of thousand or millions of lines of code we end up running every day.</p><p>A lot of people will repeat the typical mantra that we "need more programmers" for the modern economy. I have to say I've always hugely disagreed with this. A lot of the effort spent in the industry is maintaining the unmaintainable and playing whack-a-mole with the problems that bad design creates. We'd be better off with a smaller contingency of programmers and tweakers mindful of efficiency and machine resources. This is definitely something I've realized directly while I've started using UNIX operating systems.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Minor hack: Pausing all mpv videos on any screen</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#minor-hack-pausing-all-mpv-videos-on-any-screen</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 23:12:03 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>For a while I had been looking for a command to pause all mpv video instances on my computer. I have a lock script which, while locking, automatically pauses the audio from my mpd, but I had wanted a way to pause all mpv instances as well, otherwise I would have to do the potentially annoying task of getting to the right workspace and hitting pause manually. I could find a lot more "complicated" solutions where you have to start mpv on a particular socket, but I ran across a much easier and universal possibility:</p><code>xdotool search --class mpv | xargs -I % xdotool key --window % comma</code><p>Which is a pretty funny command, but works exactly how I want. If you're not familiar with xdotool, this one-liner just searchs for all <code>mpv</code> instances and sends the key <code>,</code> to each of them, which by default moves the video back by a frame and pauses it.So now I've just added this line to my lock script, so if I ever am watching something and want to leave my computer and lock it, I don't have to worry about manually pausing mpv which may be on another screeen.Also, while I've always had <code>Super+p</code> mapped to "pause/unpause mpd audio", I've mapped <code>Super+Shift+P</code> to "pause mpd and all mpv instances", running this one-liner along with the true mpd pause command.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Video on cronjobs for managing my system</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#video-on-cronjobs-for-managing-my-system</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 22:55:45 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>I just released <a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rgSxYvFWjUY">a brief video on cronjobs</a>, how to make them for new users, including the syntax, but also some of the jobs that I have run on my machine (also about the minor annoyance of specifying displays for some graphical commands).</p><p>I didn't start using cronjobs until only a couple months ago, but now I've fully integrated them into my system. As I state in the video, I do my updating via cron by havine a <code>pacman -Syuw --noconfirm</code> command run every two hours to check for and download package updates (it also gives me a preview of the number of updateable packages on my i3blocks bar). I then finalize the update when I want, but don't have to watch the downloading happen. If you want, you could just as easily remove the <code>-w</code> and have the updating done all automatically if you don't feel like you need to see what's new.</p><p>Any suggestions on new cronjobs are welcome!</p>]]></description></item><item><title>LARBS is about done</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#larbs-is-about-done</guid><pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 15:22:00 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>Holy crap, I've probably installed and reinstalled LARBS 50 times in the past couple days as I've ironed out the last kinks. I've totally rewritten <code>larbs.sh</code> twice (arguably three times) this week, but the result is fantastic.The script runs smoother than ever on the user side (a full installation takes less than 10 minutes now) and I've autistically separated the code into functions for portability and customizeability.</p><p>And boy is it.Aside from the script now being composed of easy to manipulate functions, <code>larbs.sh</code> now reads in a separate programs file (in .csv format) and can take a custom dotfiles repo as well.You can feed it a .csv like <a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/LukeSmithxyz/LARBS/blob/master/progs.csv">this one</a> and it can parse the list and install the programs in whatever way it needs to.E.g. in the setup now, untagged programs are in the main repo, programs tagged with <code>A</code> are AUR programs and <code>G</code> programs are git repositories installable with <code>make &amp;&amp; sudo make install</code>. Depending on the tag, LARBS will run a different install command as needed.Note that the last column (which is a description of the program in a verb phrase) appears at runtime to describe the program while it's installed.A nice little addition.</p><p>So you can easily setup a your own LARBS now.Since I said I was going to do real-life videos on bash scripts, I might do an explainer on this one, since I'm sure it might be generally edifying, but also very useful for people who want to extend the scripts.</p><p>Check it out: <a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/LukeSmithxyz/LARBS">LARBS on Github</a>.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Scripting in action</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#scripting-in-action</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 16:22:52 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>At the request of viewers, I might be putting out a series of videos on shell scripting in the wild. You can see the first video of this <a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YOpeXETS2z0">here</a>. I cover a small script I use for mounting USB drives on Linux, as opposed to using some fancy (bloated?) daemon or other service.</p><p>It's probably part of my sense to not trust anything I didn't write myself ;-)</p>]]></description></item><item><title>How let your root user use your main dotfiles</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#how-let-your-root-user-use-your-main-dotfiles</guid><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 15:24:13 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>When you have a single-user system, or one with only one user with sudoer access, I always used to hate that every time I became root, I'd lose the settings set in my bashrc and aliases, my vimrc and preferred directory shortcuts.About 6 months ago, I had the crazy idea to change the root user's home directory from <code>/root</code> to <code>/home/luke</code> so root would look in my main directory for all its dotfiles.</p><p>I was initially worried that this could cause some vulnerabilities, it might still, but I have to say that it's been <b>hugely</b> convenient and hasn't given me any problems in all these months, so I recommend trying it out. All you have to do is open <code>/etc/passwd</code> and change the directory on the line starting with <code>root:</code> to your typical home directory.</p><p>So whenever you log in as root, you'll still have access to all your rc settings, and will be in your familiar home folder.I didn't think of it before, but you'll also have fewer log files to have to sort through.For example, if I once worked out a compilcated shell command and am trying to look it up in my <code>.bash_history</code>, I used to have to check <code>/home/luke/.bash_history</code> <em>and</em> <code>/root/.bash_history</code> if I couldn't remember if I ran it as myself or root.Now, however, both accounts use the same history file for bash, and also other programs.</p><p>So anyway, I recommend trying it out. I'm sure I'll get a couple emails about how it could be potentially dangerous, but the convenience has been huge and I've had no problems, although I might not recommend doing this on your webserver to hedge against unknown vulnerabilities.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Download any Academic Article Free: A One-Liner</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#download-any-academic-article-free-a-one-liner</guid><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 10:55:04 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>You may know of <a target="_blank" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sci-Hub">Sci-Hub</a>, an excellent service by Alexandra Elbakyan that opens pay-walled academic articles for free public use.</p><p>The typical use of the service is to go to the main site (right now <a target="_blank" href="http://sci-hub.tw">http://sci-hub.tw</a>, it changes often due to piracy accusations), give it a link to an academic article and it will pop up a new window allowing you to download it.</p><p>This is way too much keypressing and clicking for me, and I want an browser-free way of doing this. Instead I made a line like the following to put in your <code>bashrc</code> to run a link through sci-hub and automatically download it.</p><code>shdl() { curl -O $(curl -s http://sci-hub.tw/"$@" | grep location.href | grep -o http.*pdf) ;}</code><p>Then you can simply download an article by passing the link of its preview or abstract, e.g.: <code>shdl https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007%2Fs40806-017-0133-5</code> and it will download to your current directory.</p><p>I have this as part of my <a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/LukeSmithxyz/voidrice/blob/master/.scripts/linkhandler">linkhandler</a> script, which I have my RSS reader newsboat run on desired entries in my RSS feeds. Specifically, I subscribe to many RSS feeds for academic journals, and now with this script, if I see an article I want to read, I can just run my linkhandler script and download them immediately without laboriously having to open the browser to copy the url and then paste it into sci-hub, etc. Note that in my linkhandler script, I have it detect if the link is of an academic publisher (which is a modifiable variable) and that the Sci-Hub link is also a separate variable because, as I said, it occasionally changes and I want it to be distinct.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Macs, "PCs" and the Power of Public Relations</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#macs-pcs-and-the-power-of-public-relations</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 12:52:58 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>One of the strangest turns-of-phrase that Apple has tried to hoist on the public is the term "PC" to mean all non-Apple computers.Even without delving much deeper, this is one of the most bizarre choices; Apple Mac computers are not just PCs, but they were arguably <em>the first</em> PCs&mdash;you would think that Apple would be proud of more or less inventing the idea of a Personal Computer.</p><p>Regardless, what is the <em>point</em> of the term PC to Apple advertising? Why did they run that classic series of commercials contrasting Macs and "PCs"?At a basic level, PC is just a catch-all exonym, that is, a term for all computers outside of a designated group.In reality, there's really nothing common to computers made by Lenovo, Dell, Asus and every other company that aren't also held in common with Apple computers.The only thing in common, at least, is the <em>lack</em> of the characteristic Apple weirdness (no other company is going to get rid of all their computers' important ports, for example).</p><p>Regardless, I noticed the actual public relations use of the term "PC" after I did my video on Macs&mdash;this term works wonders in the mind of an Mac fan.That is, nearly every dogmatic Apple user would call me a "PC fanboy"!<em>PC fanboy...</em> what could that possibly mean?</p><p>At first I thought most hate mail was coming from people who didn't watch 10 or so seconds in when I said that I used Linux (deliberately to avoid inane comments like this).I assumed that "PC" meant "a machine running Windows", which is clearly not what Mac-users thought the term to mean: it was <em>all</em> non-Mac computers. I'd guess that my old TI-84 calculator is a "PC" by that metric.This is a total inversion of what the term "fanboy" means of course. You can be a Mac fanboy: Apple Mac products, while sometimes different, all share the exact same design principles and are all owned by one company notorious for its quasi-cult like public relations.</p><p>While on the other hand, "PC fanboy" doesn't really mean anything&mdash;there's no common denominator or design or principle behind all non-Apple computers (again, aside from the fact that they don't do the manifestly stupid things that Apple does).A "PC fanboy" in practice just means someone who doesn't like Macs, but that's where the magic is for Apple advertising&mdash;Mac users have always been lampooned as cult members, but the term PC is an attempt redirect the claims of irrational devotion backwards.It doesn't have to make sense generally, but it makes sense in the head of an Apple fanboy: non-Mac computers are all the same and if you don't like Macs, you must just have some terrible emotional problem with them for no reason (this is the gist of most of the hatemail I get on this anyway).</p><p>Since I made my video on Macs, I don't dislike Macs any more than I did before, but I am continually losing respect for Mac users.I could've just as easily done a video on why I don't use Windows, but God knows that Windows users don't have the same genre of pathological attachment to the brand they use.That's not to imply that all comments from Mac users even disagreed with me, but the vocal members of the hivemind have certainly put a smug anime girl face on me from time to time.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>New st patches: Xresources and pywal compatibility</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#new-st-patches-xresources-and-pywal-compatibility</guid><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 20:09:57 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>When I did <a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FJmm7wl4JUI">my original video on st</a>, AKA the suckless <a target="_blank" href="https://st.suckless.org/">simple terminal</a>, a lot of other people decided to migrate over, but there are a couple of features that I hadn't added to my build, or people were confused how to add. Now, partially in preparation for LARBS, I've added some more features, including the fact that the terminal colors now use your Xresources colors by default, enabling the use of <a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/dylanaraps/pywal">wal/pywal</a> for creating universal colorschemes. (If you don't know what this is, <a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Es79N_9BblE">I did a video on it a couple months ago</a>.)</p><p>You can now check out my patched version of st <a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/LukeSmithxyz/st">right here</a>, and it will have all the best patches applied by default now.</p><p>I think it's at the point where I consider st just about the best possible terminal for me (and probably for most all people). I occationally get requests to submit by build to the AUR, which I might do, but I can definitely say that you can safely use my build and get all the features you expect from a terminal while it still being bugless and minimal as any good suckless software should be.</p><p>Well actually, on bugs, there is one little, minor annoyance in the program and that's that ranger image previews disappear when you mouse away from the given window.While there is a patch for st 0.7 which gives it sixel compatibility, due to its *le bloat* it hasn't been accepted into the program, and aside from that, I don't think ranger is built to work with sixel itself either so far.Either way, I still consider st largely "the best", but being able to patch in something like this would make it closer to "perfect". With the features and bindings I have in my build, I find it a little sad when I have to use another terminal.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>In Defense of "Pseudoscience"</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#in-defense-of-pseudoscience</guid><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 11:41:49 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>If you keep up with my random asides in videos and elsewhere, you might know that I'm extremely disappointed with the current state of institutionalized science.The post-war era was a disaster for scientific epistemology, in fact, epistemology and science commentary mostly became an exercise to exclude one's enemies by technicality.Academia became an enormous state-funded enterprise, and the best way to ensure that your research program got funding before your rivals was to develop advanced reasoning to exclude their methodology altogether from science.</p><p>Thus the term "pseudoscience".In former centuries, there was no such division between "science" and "pseudoscience".Researchers wrote tomes on subjects which were amalgams of hard analysis and what we would now consider baseless or unwarranted speculation.Each were understood for what they were, all ideas were on the table for analysis.</p><p>The thing is, all academics&mdash;at least all remotely intelligent ones&mdash;quietly harbor fringe beliefs.If you push any of them in private, or with vindicating evidence, they'll quickly bounce to support their deeper intuition.One example that comes to mind is geologist Robert Schoch, who after a little empirical prodding, became a vocal supporter of the idea of a prehistoric dating of the Sphinx, and then later other Mesolithic civilizations.Nowadays he brushes shoulders even with the ancient aliens crowd, and why shouldn't he?Once you've earned the designation of "pseudoscientist", you might as well go full-bore and have fun.</p><p>The other best-kept secret is that by definition, "pseudoscience" drives advancement in "real science".All new ideas start out as baseless speculation&mdash;Alfred Wegener's theory of continental drift, based on the trivial and child-like realization that South America sort of fits into Africa, was mocked as pseudoscientific by Americans for decades. Now it's science.I wouldn't doubt if Schoch's Sphinx water erosion hypothesis will be similarly vindicated, partially by the many Mesolithic constructions found since then.</p><p>In linguistics and archeology, we have a recent "pseudoscientist" in Marija Gimbutas.Gimbutas unearthed many female idols/dolls from pre-Indo-European Europe and jumped to far-reaching, "pseudoscientific" conclusions: Old Europe was a feminist utopia, there was no violence and complete harmony, etc.Because Gimutas's politics were socially unassailable, you don't hear "pseudoscientist" around her much, but that's certainly the word on everyone's lips.If pseudoscience is what Schoch is doing, it's certainly what she was doing.Regardless, this pushed her into making specific claims about the origin of Indo-Europeans, that they originated from the Kurgan (Yamnaya) culture, a claim that has now become consensus due to further archeological, linguistic and nowadays even genetic research.</p><p>I've seen first hand that there are really two types of personalities in science.On one had, there's the conventional and petty academic who is "detail-oriented" and "rigorous" in some sense that means religiously adherent to theoretical priors.These people will only truly fight for something when they're on the side of consensus or when the issue is of no social importance.On the other side are the "pseudoscientists", or in other words, the people who actually have something interesting to say.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Video on copying and pasting from Vim</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#video-on-copying-and-pasting-from-vim</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 15:21:27 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>A quick little video on <a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=E_rbfQqrm7g">how to copy and pasting using the system clipboard</a> in Vim. It's simple enough, but people ask me about this a whole lot. Some brief instructions about registers generally as well.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>i3blocks reloaded</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#i3blocks-reloaded</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 13:15:30 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>I've put up a video expanding on my <a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gKumet6b-WY">i3blocks status bar</a>, partially in preparation for the LARBS tutorial videos.</p><p>I've implemented many new features, including signaling for a lower footprint bar, and some other bells and whistles. I also go through where everything is in the system for people using my configs.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Monetized with Super Chats</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#monetized-with-super-chats</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 13:34:39 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>I took a long (several hour) walk to clear my head this morning, and came back to a pleasant surprise: YouTube has finally (after five or six months of review) monetized my channel.I don't have the slightest idea how much money I'll actually end up getting from this, but I hope it's decent enough.</p><p>Of course, my studious core of viewers all will be using ad-blockers. The one I usually recommend is <a href="https://adnauseam.io/">Ad Nauseam</a>, which is not just a blocker, but a dazzler. If you don't like ads, don't feel like you need to permit them from my channel to get me more revenue. I'm sure there are plenty other who will be watching them without.I only monetized after polling my audience at the old forum (some 80% just told me to monetize) and if you're part of that remaining 20%, just block them as you usually would.</p><p>The other nice detail is that I can now allow "Super Chats" in livestreams.If you don't know, that's when users can pay money to have their chat message plastered prominently in the chat window for a period proprtional to their donation.I think chats in my livestreams are off decent enough size that people would be willing to get some of these.But then again, now doing le bloodsports seems like a much more appealling prospect. Any takers?</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Redesign of Website</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#redesign-of-website</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 22:11:47 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>I've reformatted <a href="https://lukesmith.xyz/">my personal website</a> a bit, and I've readded <a href="https://lukesmith.xyz/videos.html">the video gallery</a> page which I had on my last site.YouTube is terrible about showing older videos to users, so it's nice having <em>my own</em> archive of things displayed logically.If I don't do that, I literally get oblvious questions all the time asking me to do a video on things I did a video on last week.I can hardly even blame summerfriends for that since if you're a new viewer, you have no good way of knowing what kind of stuff I've made videos on on YouTube because they never recommend non-recent videos and they have no good UI for looking someone's video history.</p><p>That's actually one of the ironies about YouTube.For all they complain about there being a drought of advertisers, they put out all the incentives for people to put out more and more junk videos constantly.It's easy to see from my side the enormous bias YouTube gives to videos that are 72 hours old, but after those 72 hours, very few people will ever see any given video unless it absolutely goes viral.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>A Journey to Athens</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#a-journey-to-athens</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 22:04:34 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>I've still been looking for apartments in Georgia or thereabout and yesterday I took a full-day trip back to Athens (Georgia of course) to scout out apartments. After a full day and after seeing about a dozen places, I have to admit that I didn't find anywhere too much up to snuff, even given the fact that I don't need to be particularly close to the university.</p><p>I may be back there again within a week or so, but I'll concede that I was debating whether I actually want to live there again.I'm really not in the mood to put down a year's rent anywhere, even if it's only $5000 or so, unless I can get a really great place, but I suppose the real problem is a change in my mindset.</p><p>In brief, I don't feel like I want to put down money for something that isn't going to last; the bugmanhood of renting an apartment is extremely unappealing.The better alternative now seems like just buying a parcel of land with the little money I've saved up.My goal is 5+ semi-remote acres for less than $20,000, which is doable. I have a couple placing I'm looking at now, but am always looking for more.I just want land that I am extremely free in building restrictions and zoning (preferable none), and that I can have a permanent setup on: possible growing and self-sustaining utilities.I've done a lot of math and think that I can get a decent cabin built (my myself) for less than $5,000, probably closer to $3,000, but maybe with $2,000 of unforeseen costs ;-)</p><p>The other thing on the ledger would be me buying a car (or more likely, a pick-up) because I haven't needed a car since honestly 10 years (my old car finally died about two years ago).Granted, if anyone reading this around Georgia has a used pickup truck in good shape they're willing to get rid of, feel free to contact me ;-)Don't rip me off though, I have a YouTube channel!</p>]]></description></item><item><title>First Imagemagick Videos</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#first-imagemagick-videos</guid><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 09:13:23 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>I've put up two videos on imagemagick today and yesterday covering some of the basics from making canvases and composites and basic effects. You can check the first out <a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ETumamLjFbg">here</a> and the second <a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nbXHbHrfrIs">here</a>. Imagemagick is one of the most useful programs out there, and can be a huge boon for automated imageprocessing and also making little modifications (like resizing and minor adjustment).</p><p>I'll be doing more like this just because of imagemagick being such a huge and useful world. Specific ideas are welcome.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Updates about Money and Patreon</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#updates-about-money-and-patreon</guid><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 20:31:52 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>First, as a reminder, I do indeed have <a target="_blank" href="https://patreon.com/lukesmith">a Patreon</a> and encourage people to join. As stiff of a veneer I pretend to have when it comes to money, I won't pretend that there is a great psychological effect to getting new patrons and bigger pledges. Now that I'm dissertating, if I can start making decent money on YouTube, it will affect a lot how much free time I'll have if I can live with on part-time work. If you don't like Patreon as a platform, donate via <a target="_blank" href="https://liberapay.com/LukeSmith">Liberapay</a> or <a target="_blank" href="https://paypal.me/lukemsmith">Paypal</a>.</p><p>I said so a couple days ago in a part of another post, but I'm switching my Patreon to being based "by creation" rather than "by month" so people get charged by content rather than time. As longer viewers know, sometimes I have to take several weeks off, while other times, I'm making videos every day.<b>If you're already a patron on Patreon, you might want to change your settings.</b>Specifically, everyone has been grandfathered in from the monthly donation scheme with those settings.If you want to pledge by creation now, you'll have to adjust the per unit donation and your maximum.  </p><p>Of course <a target="_blank" href="https://liberapay.com/LukeSmith">my Liberapay</a> is, by its nature set to on a weekly basis, so if you want a clearer time-based donation system, try them out. Liberapay, unlike Patreon, does not skim money off the top for themselves, so if you're thinking about using one of them for time-based donations and don't have any account yet, go with Liberapay.</p><p>By the way, Patreon says I'm making $180 per video, which isn't accurate. It's really more like $180 per month plus about $10 or so for the first few videos; it simply adds in the monthly donators to that number. If I could actually make near $200 per video or more, I could basically retire and do this full time ;-).</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Video on GIMP basics</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#video-on-gimp-basics</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 10:36:55 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>I've put up a video on the basics of GIMP, which you can see <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5m8Oaz8XWVI">here</a>.</p><p>I may do more in the future, but even better, I'm going to be doing some videos on Imagemagick (I already have one recorded which I'll release over the weekend). For those who don't know, Imagemagick is a core system for image creating and editing that accessible on the command line. It's hard to full express how useful IM is, so the first video will be just on one of my implementations of it.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Consciousness, bicamerality and book reviews</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#consciousness-bicamerality-and-book-reviews</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 21:47:25 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>After a good bit more reading, I've given up on <em>Hamlet's Mill</em>, and not lightly. I usually view it as a kind of shame to stop reading a book before finishing, but I frankly don't feel like it's worth it at this point. The book is far too circumambulative to actually communicate its deeper point, but I get the feeling that it's that way out of a desire on the authors' part to avoid criticism with lack of clarity.</p><p>From what I can gather (after reading several hundred pages of deep, dank, quasi-poetic prose), it's a general argument that many classic mythological stories (those stories in different cultures that <em>Hamlet</em> is based on) are a kind of folkloric embedding of knowledge of axial procession (the fact that the earth's axis wobbles every several tens of thousands of years). This point is only alluded to or barely said, and only very circumstantial arguments are made for it, at the request of readers to squint their eyes to blurry the argument to make it sound more convincing than it really is.</p><p>Instead, I've started reading Julian Jaynes' <em>The Origin of Consciousness in the Breakdown of the Bicameral Mind</em> for the third time. It's one of my favorite reads, no so much because I find it so convincing, but because it's that pleasurable mix of ancient aliens-tier imagination and speculation with at least passable science, neurology, linguistics and other research. This was an enjoyment I hoped to replicate in reading <em>Hamlet's Mill</em> actually.</p><p>I've been hinted that I might start doing book reviews at the request of many subscribers, and I might pick <em>Bicameral Mind</em> to be the first candidate after I finish it again. I put up a poll of commonly requested books on the forum, and Taleb's <em>Antifragile</em>, Herrnstein and Murray <em>Bell Curve</em> and an unspecified book by Nietzsche got the most votes, but I'll probably end up doing everything on the poll anyway.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Linux is the Wild West! Talk is now out</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#linux-is-the-wild-west-talk-is-now-out</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 13:54:29 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>I've uploaded my <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PnCXJn2cRf4">Linuxfest talk at this link</a>. Check it out. Southeast Linuxfest sends their apologies for not recording my face, but luckily I brought all the equipment for recording on my own machine.</p><p>Again, the talk was pretty packed with a lot of standers, especially considering the late time; it was great presenting and meeting all the people I did. I might be going next year as well if I have the time and hope to see all of you again (with many others).</p><p>Linuxfest also had set tables for lesser donnors to advertise their wares. At least one group was livestreaming throughout the event, and I figure that might be an option for me in the future. (I've also thought about merch, but it always strikes me as contrived and a little too consumerist.) I'm not actually sure how much they charge for the tables, but it's crossed my mind to crowdfund the money. That's probably something to think about in the future though.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Linuxfest 2018 review</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#linuxfest-2018-review</guid><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 10:43:34 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>A brief video on my experience at Southeast Linuxfest, check it out <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EhwSoZAHo-c">here</a>.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Syncthing video, also Patreon changes</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#syncthing-video-also-patreon-changes</guid><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 09:36:10 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>New video out on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8bHdcfVzrgk">Syncthing</a> for keeping files in sync.</p><p>I've said this on Patreon already, but I'm going to be moving to a "per creation" payout on Patreon rather than the "per month" payout. I figure that'd (1) be more fair to people when I go another month like the last one where I don't put much out and (2) give some incentive for me to put stuff out regularly when I'm not moving cross-country or something. I'll treat all contentful videos as "paid" videos, meaning that I won't charge patrons for meta-videos or personal updates. For example, I'll be putting one out today or tomorrow on Liunxfest, etc.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>The Secrets in Hamlet's Mill</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#the-secrets-in-hamlets-mill</guid><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 23:40:48 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>A week or so ago, I heard about, for the first time, the book <em>Hamlet's Mill: An Essay Investigating the Origins of Human Knowledge and Its Transmission Through Myth</em>. The subtitle should communicate the gist. After ordering it online, it arrived this afternoon and I've gotten five chapters in (barely a fifth of the way through the whole thing).</p><p>I was attracted to the book as part of my general sympathy for the idea that pre-classical and primeval knowledge and myth is, to use a silly word <em>scientific</em>, or at least true in a astronomical or quasi-metaphorical level. That's certainly the intended argument of the book, but it certainly labors under that Moldbuggian tendency to beat around the bush quietly, hoping that the deeper argument will eventually sneak up and hit its reader on the head. While the book is definitely designed to be a slow burn, one positive aspect is authors' repeated insistence of the imperfectness of translating early writings and myths, partially on linguistic grounds, but even more so due to the severely underestimated difference between the modern and primeval mindset.</p><p>I'll also say that in addition to this book, I've also bought <em>Pandora's Seed</em> (Spencer Wells) and the notable <em>Forbidden Archaeology</em> (Michael Cremo), both of which I'll hopefully be going through this week. The latter book I bought with not too much expectation of seriousness, but out of raw curiosity. It argues an extremely ancient origin of mankind based on reinterpretation of archaeological evidence, its author being what could be described as a Vedic Creationist. I don't expect to be convinced or even unannoyed by the book, but I'm always interested in circumstantial evidence for an earlier date for human evolution, especially given the constant pushing back of the accepted date.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Lol Linuxfest</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#lol-linuxfest</guid><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 00:12:46 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>I've been at Southeast Linuxfest the past two days. I'll probably do a full review later, but here are some highlights so far.</p><ul><li>My subscribers are not nearly as weird as I anticipated, and seem to be actually less weird than the average Linux user.</li><li>There actually were some girls Linuxfest (although no obvious <font color="green">&gt;girls</font>).</li><li>My talk was pretty crowded; standing room only. It also generated a lot of good discussion. I polled the audience and about half of them knew me (usually the younger ones).</li><li>Some boomer guy began to unironically "Interject" to my use of the term "Linux" as I used it in the talk ;-)</li><li>I even had a very young fan (as in utterly prepubescent fan) besting even Pewdiepie's fans in youth. He asked for an autograph and picture.</li><li>Linuxfest was generally well-organized but there were some huge oversights. The rooms were only equipped to handle HDMI inputs. This basically ruined Michael Tunnell's presentation which was right before mine (and probably others) since they couldn't record from his laptop. Poor guy had to use some useless Chromebook (which its distinct lack of keys) to try to preview kdenlive. They couldn't record from mine either, but I'm not going to let that happen, so I just went Harambe Mindframe and connected to the screen VGA input, bypassing their recording rig and recorded the talk on my own machine. This is something that the speakers should not have to be worrying about.</li><li>People got a little peeved by the organizer's keynote, because it went way, way over on time, and then was followed by another talk that ruffled some vocal SJW feathers (basically a critique of witch-hunting codes of conduct). This is just what I gleamed from people, all of whom were really tired after a long day, because I sat these talks out.</li></ul><p>Anyway, it's been nice meeting all of you who have/had come! Again, I might do a video update after the whole thing is over.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Exile in Suburbia</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#exile-in-suburbia</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 18:24:26 -0400</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>While I'm looking for a new apartment or land to live on, I've been living in the Atlanta suburbs (or 'boondocks' in some people's definitions) again. After a couple days of rest after the grueling move/drive across country, I'm getting used to the 40 minute walk to the closest town and the extreme lack of people of my demographics (both age and race).</p><p>I found a local bookstore today and bought a copy of Cochran and Harpending's <em>The 10,000 Year Explosion</em>, a book I had read a while ago, but never bought. It's actually my style to only buy books after reading them and liking them at libraries. I'm rereading it now.</p><p>I've also been going thru A.J. Ayer's <em>Language, Truth and Logic</em>, which was largely one of the key books in spreading Logical Positivism to the English-speaking work. Intellectually-subtle viewers may know that I'm not a big fan of Logical Positivism&mdash;in fact I'm sort of reading it to have a strawman to attack in my dissertation. You never know though; I find it very difficult to enunciate my distaste of it. The vocabulary isn't quite out there to do so with a popular (or un-popular) audience.</p><p>Since I plan on my dissertation being in large part philosophy of science and then some, I'll have to overcome this lack of vocabulary, and might do so partially with the aid of my YouTube channel.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Whomst lives in Georgia?</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#whomst-lives-in-georgia</guid><pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 18:05:00 -0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>Friendship ended with Arizona; now Georgia is my best friend.</p><p>I just finished my move from Arizona, which is more relieving than I can possibly express. Classwork is done, and the only possible reason I'll ever be returning to that quite literal hell-hole is for when I defend my dissertation and my graduation ceremony.</p><p>The thing is, while I've moved from Arizona, I haven't really moved anywhere in particular; I'll be living with family and friends until I decided where I want to live exactly. Here are my options:</p><ul>    <li>Just go full innawoods right now, buy land (in Georgia or Tennessee) with my money and get started. The disadvantage is that I don't have as much money as I'd like to get a choice parcel, and this would also interfere with my dissertation (perhaps it doesn't matter of course).</li>    <li>Partial innawoods. I have some family in Florida with remote land and farmhouses. I could ask to live their and watch the property, maybe practice for real innawoods hours in the meantime. No money required other than my food, unless the relevant family member wants nominal rent.</li>    <li>Move to an apartment in a practical place to work on my dissertation. This would probably mean a college town where they have a library and bus system (probably Athens, where the University of Georgia is, where I've lived before and have friends, but I don't particularly like the place). Work on the dissertation and finish in a year, then go elsewhere.</li>    <li>Move into Atlanta, get an internship at an NGO, become a bugman (joke choice).</li></ul><p>Other data:</p><ul>    <li>I don't own a car anymore and don't want to buy one unless I go innawoods. I'll need a truck if I do. Having a car while living in a city is a waste.</li>    <li>I'll <em>possibly</em> still be getting some amount of money from the University of Arizona for online work. This means that I'll have an income stream. I want to treat this income as going directly into the innawoods fund though.</li>    <li>If I actually ever get monetized (it's been 5 months of "review"), I might actually be making workable money on YouTube (possibly enough for rent somewhere). Patreon/Paypal is small now, but a lot more than nothing and sort of pays for my groceries and such.</li></ul><p>Anyway, the title of the post is "Whomst lives in Georgia?" because I'm curious. I know some subscribers live in Athens, and if there are a lot there, or a lot in Kennesaw or another college town, that might be a reason to move there, so we can have IRL meetups or stuff or I can do stuff at university events, etc. Feel free to respond to <a target="_blank" href="https://forum.lukesmith.xyz/showthread.php?tid=82">the thread on this on the forum</a> or if you don't want to dox yourself, just mail me (<a href="mailto:luke@lukesmith.xyz">luke@lukesmith.xyz</a>). </p>]]></description></item><item><title>Series on Old Norse and Language Learning?</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#series-on-old-norse-and-language-learning</guid><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 18:23:48 -0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>One request I get a whole lot is to talk about how to learn a language, or one harder, a language using only a book. I could just "talk" about it, but I figure doing it real time might be a lot better. I taught myself Latin this way nearly 10 years ago, and now use my Latin knowledge all the time academically. Part of my knowledge of Chinese also comes from my particular method of learning.</p><p>Anyway, I want to record myself going through an introductory language-learning book, verbally externalize my thoughts to make it clear how I interpret what I see. Obviously I have a lot of initial knowledge about languages generally, but as it comes up, I'll mention and explain all the needed concept  and why they're relevant.</p><p>The language I've chosen to learn is Old Norse/Old Icelandic, which, as it happens, is very close and mutually intelligible with modern Icelandic with some minor differences. WhyOld Norse? (1) It's an ancient language that can be useful for my own understanding of historical linguistics, and the development of Germanic languages, (2) it still has some older linguistic properties that will keep viewers informed of a more highly inflected language, but (3) it also has a vocabulary similar to English, which will minimize the rote memorization aspect of learning it.</p><p>The book I'll probably be going through is <em>Old Icelandic: An Introductory Course</em> by Valfells and Cathey. I'll either have a physical copy or a pdf of it, which ever ismore convenient for recording. If you have any other suggestions, feel free to give me them! Again, the point of the series isn't supposed to be just on Old Norse/Icelandic, but on language learning generally, so everyone is welcome to watch! ;-)</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Stream soon</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#stream-soon</guid><pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 10:23:59 -0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>I'll be doing a stream in a bit, probably within the hour. Keep your eyes peeled on YouTube.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Forum now has HTTP &amp; SSL (Lunduke BTFO once again)</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#forum-now-has-http--ssl-lunduke-btfo-once-again</guid><pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 20:03:14 -0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>I've finally put HTTPS on <a href="https://forum.lukesmith.xyz">the forum</a> for security's sake. I appreciate that people have been signing up already anyway. I'll probably reannounce it on the channel when I do a live stream probably tomorrow.</p><p>You may've noticed that there was also some server downtime, that was actually relevant to the SLL upgrade. I stupidly miswrote something and broke my Apache server for a minute or two. All fixed now though.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>How I Write Accent Marks and IPA Characters in Vim</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#how-i-write-accent-marks-and-ipa-characters-in-vim</guid><pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 13:54:58 -0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>I just released a brief video on <a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WPvvOEiiF28">how I put special characters into vim.</a>. There is a built in system (with control-k) for inputting special characters, but it's not as manipulatable as I'd like. Instead, I have two little vim files that coin functions to enable/disable deadkeys (for diacritics) or extra shortcuts for characters in the International Phonetic Alphabet.</p><p>The deadkey function turns ', ", :, ` and other symbols into deadkeys that place diacritics onto different characters. The IPA function is similar, but allows a sequence of semicolon plus two letters to correspond to an IPA symbol. E.g., if I want to type '?', I just type ';sh.</p><p>The links are in the video description (the files are in the voidrice repository as usual). The system is pretty customizable, and you can easily add whatever characters you need, potentially imitating the toggling commands I have there already.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Video on the blog system</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#video-on-the-blog-system</guid><pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 09:43:03 -0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>I just put up the video on the blog system, if you're interested. Check it out <a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jIfAdzGmhik">here</a>.</p><p>Again, the link to the Github repo is <a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/lukesmithxyz/lb">here</a>. Enjoy!</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Guests now allowed on forum; Perks for supporters.</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#guests-now-allowed-on-forum-perks-for-supporters.</guid><pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 09:14:04 -0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>Now that the forum is being reborn, I've openned up one of the subforums, the <a target="_blank" href="http://forum.lukesmith.xyz/forumdisplay.php?fid=5">tech support</a> one to non-registered posters. This makes it so people without an account can come and ask questions.</p><p>Additionally, I'm going to give perks to people who support me/the channel on Patreon. For now, it's going to be for anyone who gives any ammount of money, but I make increase the required input in a bit. Perks will include a gold-plated name, access to a private forum, and possibly other abilities like bigger avatar size and such (that's not implemented yet).</p>]]></description></item><item><title>More tinkering today</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#more-tinkering-today</guid><pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 13:36:26 -0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>I'm changing a couple lines in the blog script (<code>lb</code>) that beautify the standalone pages, giving them UTF-8 encoding, actual titles and the website's stylesheet. While the standalone pages were originally an afterthought, I'm sure someone will like using them. I'll also probably put a video up about the blog system anyway<p><p>I've also been working on the forum today, and I'll also be putting up an update to the mutt-wizard which will hopefully fix compatibility with certain sites. Originally, I made the apparently improper and pessimistic assumption that some providers don't use +INBOX as the inbox location, encouraging me to writing a very skiddie line in grep to filter out all non-inbox boxes to smartly guess the true inbox. This caused the system to detect people's "Contacts" or "SMS" folders as their inbox in some cases.</p><p>I'll be fixing this soon so that it always just assumes that "+INBOX" is the real thing, which I think will lessen the errors people have.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Check Github for the blog system</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#check-github-for-the-blog-system</guid><pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 15:13:06 -0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>I put my new blog system on Github. Again, just a little 70-ish line script that generates HTML and RSS/XML code automatically from a post; it'll get me a lot for very little, and obviously doesn't involve any silly databases.</p><p>Check out the link at <a href="https://github.com/LukeSmithxyz/lb">https://github.com/LukeSmithxyz/lb</a>. Play around with it if you're interested in it for your own purposes. I might do a video on it in a bit, and I'll be refining it as needed.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Excuse the RSS mess!</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#excuse-the-rss-mess</guid><pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 10:38:11 -0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>As I said, in a post before, I'm figuring out a new blogging and RSS feed paradigm which has been 95% done for several days, barring those little annoyances. I've been moving things around, including the GUIDs for RSS entires, so you may be seeing double, triple or quadruple entries in your RSS feed reader.</p><p>Feel free to purge your RSS feed cache to fix this. You won't lose anything since I have everything on my RSS feed (I'm not one of those people who has a rolling 15 entry RSS feed).</p>]]></description></item><item><title>New Forum Up and Under Preparation</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#new-forum-up-and-under-preparation</guid><pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 09:23:55 -0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>My subscriberbase has been pretty consistently dogging me to put the forum up. I figured I might as well just start a new forum with updated myBB software now. The old forum was a good trial run, but with newer software and now on my own server, there are more possibilities for a longterm forum.</p><p>So check out <a target="_blank" href="http://forum.lukesmith.xyz">forum.lukesmith.xyz</a> and go ahead and register the name you want and start posting if you'd like. As a minor warning, I don't have https for the forum yet, but that will come pretty soon.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>On my new blog system</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#on-my-new-blog-system</guid><pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 15:09:10 -0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>For the past day or so, I've been "writing" a blog "system". Really it's only about 100 lines in shell script, which sure as hell beats installing WordPress and having huge databases on the server.</p><p>I want to have one rolling blog page, automatic RSS feed updates and maybe even standalone pages, so that's what I wrote. I also want to be able to link to individual blog entries on the rolling page, so I have it automatically label each header for the use of interior urls.</p><p>If you're reading this, wherever you're reading it, it's been successfuly.</p><p>Really all the script does is let you write a HTML draft entry, and when you're done, it appends it to the rolling page and converts its information into an RSS feed entry and appends it to your RSS feed. "Append" is probably the wrong word though, since it's not being added to the end, but in front of other entries.</p><p>Anyway, I hope to be able to have a fully functioning and synced blog and RSS feed, without the hassle or bloat, now I'm pretty confident that I'm right about at it. The only thing I haven't implemented (and might not) is the ability to change and delete posts from the RSS/rolling blog/standalone page directory. I'm the kind of person who doesn't believe in revision though, so maybe I'll slide without that.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>New turbo-minimalist site</title><guid>https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html#new-turbo-minimalist-site</guid><pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 14:53:20 -0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>I've decided to severely trim down my website, not in content, but in frills. We'll see how this works out, and if it does, I plan on keeping it this way with maybe minor beautification.</p><p>At a surface level, my site is just going to be two main HTML pages: the <a target="_blank" href="http://lukesmith.xyz/index.html">main page</a> and <a href="https://lukesmith.xyz/2018.html">a blog/updates page</a> which I have made automatically (This also includes RSS updates).</p><p>One of the other things I've made use of is an Apache server's capability to display directory contents in and index page. You've probably seen things like this, see one of mine at <a target="_blank" href="http://lukesmith.xyz/talks/">talks/</a>. You can also give these pages CSS and descriptions for the files, which I've decided to take advantage of. It seems like a much better way of organizing files on your website and making them accessible than doing it manually in HTML.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Why Vim Doesn't Need a Mouse (video)</title><guid isPermaLink="false">vimmouse</guid><pubDate> Fri, 11 May 2018 10:52:21 -0700</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tQCRVkSFFEc</link><description><![CDATA[<p>A brief video on why vim doesn't use the mouse, and how to do "mouse-like" things like selection and movement.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>I'll be at Linux Fest Southeast next month. Come and see me!</title><guid isPermaLink="false">linuxfestintro</guid><pubDate> Sun, 06 May 2018 13:16:41 -0700</pubDate><link>http://www.southeastlinuxfest.org/</link><description><![CDATA[<p>I mentioned this in a video or two, but I'll be presenting at Southeast Linuxfest in Charlotte, NC on June 9. Feel free to come if you're in the Southeast. There are actually going to be a lot of talks all weekend, but mine is currently slated for June 9th (Saturday), the last talk of the day.</p><p>I should be in town for the full duration of the conference though. I'll also probably be recording the talk as well. I think the conference managers have recorded them in the past, but I want to be sure of the audio quality. Either way, it'll end up on YouTube. That said, for those in neighboring or nearby states, I think it'd be worth your time to come, not just for me, but for all the talks, tutorials, sessions and groups there to choose from. Check out their website for more: <a href="http://www.southeastlinuxfest.org/">http://www.southeastlinuxfest.org/</a></p>]]></description></item><item><title>What a waste of time!</title><guid isPermaLink="false">timewaste</guid><pubDate> Fri, 04 May 2018 09:17:05 -0700</pubDate><link>https://lukesmith.xyz</link><description><![CDATA[<p>Welp I've spent about a week moving my websites to a VPS (several attempts at different services actually). I've only just now finally had some success. I originally was going to try Digital Ocean, but they don't offer good email service. I tried setting up an email server myself, but the amount of work and number of details needed to get everything to work is an order of magnitude more than just running a web server.</p><p>So I'm actually using a Namecheap VPS now, which is the registrar of my domains anyway. I thought this would make transferring my hosting easy (It wasn't). Namecheap has atrocious documentation and their site is extremely slow and non-responsive (thankfully their hosting servers/VPSs aren't). Regardless, I've gotten my website working (with https) and my email with their email service after several days of making DNS changes blindly and checking the results on update 24 hours later.</p><p>On a side note, SSL is one of the more difficult things to configure manually. While there are tools like Let's Encrypt, they can often be a pain to get working with different hosts and especially when you're like me and want wildcard certificates for your multiple sites. I really do not understand why hosts don't automate this process for most use cases (actually I do, because most of them get money off of selling partial automation).</p><p>Anyway, the looming issue is the forum. Host Gator automatically installed the (outdated) myBB backend for the forum, so I've never done the process myself manually. I'm going to have to figure that out soon enough, which will require me to get some mySQL database up and running (again, I've never done this before).</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Updates on downtime and server transfer/email</title><guid isPermaLink="false">transfernamecheap</guid><pubDate> Tue, 01 May 2018 12:59:08 -0700</pubDate><link>https://forum.lukesmith.xyz/thread-537.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>The link is to a forum thread on the topic. I've had a lot of trouble configuring email manually, so I'm going to get a VPS + email server from namecheap instead. I should be able to receive email alright at the time being and the forum will be up.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Moving to a VPS, some downtime</title><guid isPermaLink="false">vpsmove</guid><pubDate> Sat, 28 Apr 2018 14:55:59 -0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>I'm in the process of moving the entire website/LARBS/the forum to a VPS, due to the annoying practices of my former host, HostGator. Expect some downtime or certificate errors. My main website and this feed should be done (that's the easy part).</p><p>Hopefully I'll have LARBS.xyz finished today as well, but the forum might take another day, just because I have to go through the rigmarole of installing myBB manually on my new server which I haven't done before. That said, I managed to figure out how to install/run/configure an Apache server this morning so I figure myBB can't be much more difficult.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Playing around with i3 blocks (video)</title><guid isPermaLink="false">i3blocks</guid><pubDate> Mon, 23 Apr 2018 08:04:29 -0700</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n7_9Xdbsem4</link><description><![CDATA[<p>I've had some wanderlust for having a more configurable status bar, so I got back into i3blocks. I manages to create some custom blocks, including one for unread emails and one for a weather report. Check it out and maybe you'll get some ideas yourself.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Some tips in a vim project (video)</title><guid isPermaLink="false">vimsublimeslave</guid><pubDate> Sun, 22 Apr 2018 11:49:26 -0700</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hraHAZ1-RaM</link><description><![CDATA[<p>A little vid on some vim tips and how to customize a workflow for your particular tasks. The content is mostly on how I turned raw file names into easily adjustable links for a personal task.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Arch Install Part 2: Setting up a graphical environment and users (video)</title><guid isPermaLink="false">arch2</guid><pubDate> Sat, 21 Apr 2018 14:27:39 -0700</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nSHOb8YU9Gw</link><description><![CDATA[<p>A follow up on the Arch install video, talking about how to install a graphical environment and other basic setup tips.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Video on newsboat and RSS feed (video)</title><guid isPermaLink="false">newsboat</guid><pubDate> Wed, 11 Apr 2018 09:42:50 -0700</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dUFCRqs822w</link><description><![CDATA[<p>A little video on newsboat and RSS feeds. Welcome, if you're just now getting into RSS feeds!</p>]]></description></item><item><title>dmenu is more than an "application launcher"! (video)</title><guid isPermaLink="false">dmenu1</guid><pubDate> Sat, 07 Apr 2018 11:37:53 -0700</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R9m723tAurA</link><description><![CDATA[<p>I've been playing around with dmenu a little recently, and the way it was intended to be used! In this video, I show some little scripts that exploit dmenu's extensibility to get a lot of functionality out of this little suckless program.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>wtf i hate linux now! Mac OS is best, and other comments.</title><guid isPermaLink="false">aprilfools2018</guid><pubDate> Sat, 31 Mar 2018 22:25:03 -0700</pubDate><link>https://forum.lukesmith.xyz/thread-426.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>I gave the forum a little makeover</p>]]></description></item><item><title>tripcode!Q/7 fixes my X220</title><guid isPermaLink="false">tripcodex220video</guid><pubDate> Mon, 26 Mar 2018 13:47:26 -0700</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zV1f8raveZo</link><description><![CDATA[<p>Watch tripcode!Q/7's video repairing my X220. It's all there!</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Oral defense next week</title><guid isPermaLink="false">oralssoon</guid><pubDate> Fri, 23 Mar 2018 15:01:12 -0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>I've been preparing for my oral defense in my doctoral program and some other things recently, adding up to one of the more full months I've had in a while. (So if you're curious why I haven't been putting up as much as usual, that's why). For those who don't know what this means, I wrote two qualifying papers as required for my PhD, and afterwards, our department requires an oral defense of both of them, in front of a committee of my choosing from the department.</p><p>For those who want to know, my committee is Mike Hammond, Tom Bever, Massimo Piatelli-Palmarini, Simin Karimi and Robert Henderson. The only one who non-linguists may be familiar with is Massimo, notorious for his book "What Darwin Got Wrong" with Jerry Fodor, but a couple of the others might have a Wikipedia article or talks on YouTUbe if anyone is interested.</p><p>Anyway, after passing this, I'll be officially allowed to start on my dissertation (and after finishing that, I'll be doing another defense of that). I was sort of thinking of recording this defense for public consumption, although I don't think I'm strictly speaking allowed to, as the event is supposed to be private. (I think this has traditionally been just for the privacy of the defender, which I obviously don't care about).</p><p>After this is over, I'll the ABD (all but dissertation, as they say) and will have more time on my hands.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>LiberaPay now added (It's better than Paypal and Patreon)</title><guid isPermaLink="false">liberapay</guid><pubDate> Thu, 22 Mar 2018 09:52:16 -0700</pubDate><link>https://liberapay.com/LukeSmith</link><description><![CDATA[<p>A lot of people said that they'd like to fund the channel/me, but are (understandably) nervous about Patreon and Paypal. I've now added a <a href="https://liberapay.com/LukeSmith">LiberaPay account</a>, which is a much freer and privacy respecting platform, which also doesn't take a slice off the top fo every transfer.</p><p>If you don't trust Patreon or Paypal (which you shouldn't really), throw your support in via LiberaPay. It'd honestly be better generally to get channel funding there anyway!</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Luke Smith and Noam Chomsky (and my position in the field)</title><guid isPermaLink="false">meetnoam</guid><pubDate> Sat, 17 Mar 2018 22:47:18 -0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>Noam Chomsky and I finally formally met this evening at Simin Karimi's Noruz Party. We've run into each other in the halls from time to time, but this was the first time we officially spoke. This sounds like a somewhat bloggish thing to mention, and knowing me, I felt no overwhelming need to speak with him, but Tom Bever insisted on introducing us.</p><p>Tom introduced me in too glowing terms, a nice, yet not so meaningful gesture considering Noam is more than half deaf nowadays, especially in the bustle of the party. People had actually be lining up to see him; it looked sort of like people paying respect to a mafia don, but Tom unceremoniously pushed aside everyone else and invited me to talk to Noam directly.</p><p>We spoke a bit about my projects on prosodically driven syntax and the quantifier scope project, and he entreated me to talk to him later to get more in depth. He didn't divulge if he knew about me, granted, he's definitely heard of me from Tom and others in the department and we've spoken on email chains, but I'm not sure what or if he could've been expected to remember considering that he's less involved than the other faculty.</p><p>I still don't plan on going into the field, but there was an aura of momentousness to the event. A couple people were taking pictures of us and I got a couple comments afterward that remarked on the potential significance of our first meeting.</p><p>Either way it is sort of funny. Someone mentioned to me a bit ago that a lot of the grad students in the field know Arizona as "the place where Luke Smith is", which is hilarious for many reasons, and would probably be upsetting for a lot of the syntacticians here, but most strange now that Noam is here (a lot of people assume he's still at MIT since it's only been a year or so). I've never been plugged into academic politics, I don't actually plan on publishing before I leave the field and I've never even been to the LSA, but between the YouTube channel and targeted pressure from several people, I have a level of notoriety unexpected by me.</p><p>So the disaster scenario for "some people out there" is that something comes of this: that I become in the popular eye "the Linguist" that at least some normal people know about, or even worse, some kind of next logical step from Chomsky, catapulted to prominence in a way similar to how Noam's political rabble-rousing popularized him. And of course the elephant in the room is the political differences: there's a huge irony in some kind of mantle being passed from a Jewish anarcho-communist who grew up on a kibbutz to a goyish low-church Borderer who voted for Trump and has only barely managed to slip into the cracks of academia given his political disposition. If I were to obtain a well-known position in academia, I would be doing a lot of good for the re-enfranchisement of the White Right in the opinion-molding class.</p><p>That's not to say that my ascendancy in the field is even probable if I do stay, but the mere fact there's greater than a 2% chance of it would certainly have surprised me 15, 10, 5 or even 2 years ago. The only question is what aspects of my life am I willing to give up to continue to stoke the fires of this potentiality, or if I can continue to tolerate this lifestyle. On one hand, I've put up with every lie, manipulation, character assassination and "technicality" that could be thrown at me from this department, mostly without flinching, and my detractors are starting to sound like boys-who-cried-wolfs. On the other hand, a cabin for my family in the woods generally sounds like a better lifestyle.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Linguistics Isn't 60 Years Old!:P??inian Approaches to Language</title><guid isPermaLink="false">paninisimin</guid><pubDate> Thu, 15 Mar 2018 17:53:51 -0700</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8yZ91YUdRfY</link><description><![CDATA[<p>A guest lecture I gave in Simin Karimi's "Major Works in Syntax" class, a very brief talk about the Indian/Paninian tradition in linguistics. She expressed interest in having me again, so there might be a Part 2 to this focusing on mostly Medieval European thought.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>New LARBS format; 2.0 coming soon.</title><guid isPermaLink="false">larbscoming</guid><pubDate> Sat, 10 Mar 2018 19:36:15 -0700</pubDate><link>https://github.com/lukesmithxyz/larbs</link><description><![CDATA[<p>I've developed a more robust framework for implementing LARBS that will make it considerably easier and more elegant to manage packages. Now all packages are read in one single csv file and are processed based on whether the user chose their package group and whether the package is in the main repos or only in the AUR (this detection is now done automatically).</p><p>There's also now a (mostly) ncurses based interface during installation and, if it means anything, I've considerably reduced the size of the script seeing that the deployment method is now less <i>ad hoc</i>.</p><p>I'm hoping to "officially" re-release the scripts very soon, in fact, after this they may not actually change much at all until I do, all is needed is a little testing. You're welcome to try it yourself now and see the results.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>I've been unironically playing the best game ever again: Deus Ex</title><guid isPermaLink="false">deusexinstall</guid><pubDate> Fri, 09 Mar 2018 12:59:44 -0700</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<p>I installed Deus Ex (yes, of course the original) on my Arch Desktop, just for laughs and because I wanted to quickly replay and get tired of it. Installation on Linux wasn't too difficult since there's an OpenGL renderer from the Mac port, and aside from that all I needed to install was some lib32 pulseaudio/alsa things. It runs really smooth and clean on a Linux machine if it means anything.</p><p>Don't expect me to end up becoming a game streamer, especially with (&gt;proprietary software), but it was fairly refreshing to play a game with genuinely good storyline and development again. Obviously it lacks the features of a modern game, but back then video games were far enough away from real life so that you could rely on your imagination to fill in the gaps, which arguably makes for a better experience.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Suckless sent of video creation?</title><guid isPermaLink="false">sentvideos</guid><pubDate> Thu, 08 Mar 2018 14:44:19 -0700</pubDate><link>https://tools.suckless.org/sent/</link><description><![CDATA[<p>A little bit ago I talked about how I've been using suckless <a href="https://tools.suckless.org/sent/">sent</a>, which is a minimalist presentation format. It lacks features aside from the basics: text on slides (which is automatically sized for each one) and the ability to have images (only one per slide, again, autosized).</p><p>I've always looked for a more effective way to make meme videos, by which I mean the videos like my distro-hopping or Mac videos, where I more or less narrate a stream of memes and some text. Traditionally I did this in Blender, but that could be very time consuming, taking several days of constant work to put out a 10 minute video.</p><p>It actually hit me that sent would be a very good replacement for Blender (strangely enough), in that I can just write a presentation, put in images, etc., load it in sent, and record my screen while narrating. I.e., no video editing/tweaking/compiling or work time other than assembling my "script" for the video, in the different memes and text I'll be talking about.</p><p>I think I'll try this out pretty soon. Hopefully I can get in a place where I can put videos like that out relatively commonly.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Arch Linux: Is it a meme? (video)</title><guid isPermaLink="false">archisameme</guid><pubDate> Thu, 08 Mar 2018 11:56:22 -0700</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VO9R_WFs9Zc</link><description><![CDATA[<p>Here I talk about some misunderstandings about Arch Linux and some reasons it's worth using. It's not the best distro (there is none), but I keep coming back to Arch for a couple reasons.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>mutt-wizard Now Has an Autosync and Notification Option!</title><guid isPermaLink="false">muttwizsync</guid><pubDate> Tue, 06 Mar 2018 10:28:20 -0700</pubDate><link>https://github.com/LukeSmithxyz/mutt-wizard</link><description><![CDATA[<p>I've added a new options to the mutt-wizard which will automatically add a cronjob that runs a script that smartly syncs offlineimap at the interval you want if there's an internet connection.</p><p>It also checks to see if new mail has been downloaded, and if it has, will provide a brief little notification ding! Enjoy!</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Clean out your RSS feed cache!</title><guid isPermaLink="false">rssfeedclean</guid><pubDate> Mon, 05 Mar 2018 19:01:27 -0700</pubDate><link>https://lukesmith.xyz</link><description><![CDATA[<p>I've cleaned up and added all the frills to my RSS feed to maximize the compatibility with different readings. The temporary downside is that long-time users will probably have to clean out their RSS cache for my feed, otherwise you'll see lots of duplicate entries!</p><p>Don't be afraid, everything will still be here, but you can fee free to clean out your RSS cache and reload to clean everything up!</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Quantifier Scope Is All Just Fun and Games! (video)</title><pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 16:50:57 MST</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5w_PMpQiGL0</link><description><![CDATA[<p>A presentation I gave a couple weeks back to prospective graduate students on a recent linguistics project. I argued that quantifier scope is extra-linguistic, not determined by the narrow syntax and am building, with some colleagues a general account of quantifier scope in Game Theoretic terms.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">funandgames</guid></item><item><title>From Arch Linux to Parabola: How-To and System Management! (video)</title><pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 20:51:30 MST</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4Jx-5Zp28VQ</link><description><![CDATA[<p>In this video I go through how to migrate an Arch Linux install to Parabola GNU/Linux-libre, which is a 100% free software distribution! Check it out!</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">arch2para</guid></item><item><title>NEWS: Arch Linux Install and Config; and X220 Repair (video)</title><pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 23:25:54 MST</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6Ke9ZNC9a5k</link><description><![CDATA[<p>tripcode!Q/7, who also makes YouTube videos, volunteered to try to fix my X220, so I'll be sending it to him next week. Also, two major Patreon incentives were met last month: the Arch Linux install and the Arch Linux graphical environment setup! Expect those within a week or so!</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">tripcode</guid></item><item><title>BRAINLET Luke Destroys his ThinkPad X220!!! (Press F) (video)</title><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 10:40:23 MST</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3X1LUlnhIAI</link><description><![CDATA[<p>Check the video out! When fixing my X220 I made some bad electrical contact and fried the screen connector. What does this mean for the channel? Let's find out!</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">destx220</guid></item><item><title>Easy, No BS Slide Presentations with SENT! (suckless) (video)</title><pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 11:28:15 MST</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aCLCl96eNaI</link><description><![CDATA[<p>I've been playing around with sent recently, which is a good way to immediately make slide presentations. Check it out!</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">sucklesssent</guid></item><item><title>You're not "Autistic." You're normal. (video)</title><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 11:42:49 MST</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YAsxztU189k</link><description><![CDATA[<p>I wanted to talk about a mindset I get a lot from some of my subscribers. Sure, a lot of it is just making fun, but some people get hard on themselves for having hobbies or not socializing how they think they should be. I address this in this video.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">autistic</guid></item><item><title>Now You Can Auto-Configure Mutt and OfflineIMAP! (video)</title><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 23:08:29 MST</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SsEJz9f9VMQ</link><description><![CDATA[<p>Video out on the now completed mutt/offlineIMAP wizard. Try it yourself! It will give a fully featured terminal email setup with offline backups for offline browsering and safe password storage.</p><p>I also put out a brief video on how to generate a public/private key pair in GnuPG <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DMGIlj7u7Eo">here</a>, which is needed for the auto-confige script.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">muttwiz</guid></item><item><title>Working on a email wizard for mutt and offlineIMAP configs</title><pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 08:31:10 MST</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1h-Qr_Ricik</link><description><![CDATA[<p>A brief video showing what I have so far on the mutt auto-config.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">muttwizprep</guid></item><item><title>Working on a mutt wizard</title><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 23:55:54 MST</pubDate><link>https://github.com/LukeSmithxyz/mutt-wizard</link><description><![CDATA[<p>I think I'll put a video up on this tomorrow, but I'm starting to put together an ncurses script that will automatically configure mutt, offlineIMAP, notmuch, and everything else you need for a fully featured offline terminal email service, all with basically no user effort beyond putting in their email and password.</p><p>If you're a mutt user, you can help me by sending me your email server settings if they're not already in the autoconf/domains.csv file.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">muttwiznot</guid></item><item><title>We Have a Forum! (and on the Future!)</title><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 16:41:35 MST</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5MC3wR63FHs</link><description><![CDATA[<p>I hope you enjoyed the brief week of no newfriends on the forum. In this video I announce the forum to the wider channel and talk about some of my plans in the near future.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">forumvid</guid></item><item><title>How to Actually Get Good at GNU/Linux (video)</title><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 09:46:52 MST</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nNuz-Trx0a4</link><description><![CDATA[<p>A daily reminder on the importance of RTFMing!</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">man</guid></item><item><title>i3: Managing Windows and Webcams for screencasting</title><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 09:00:07 MST</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JkqxYZ7-sQM</link><description><![CDATA[<p>A little vid on window management in i3wm, where I show how I manage my webcam and keep it with the properties I want.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">i3webcams</guid></item><item><title>Dropdown Terminals and Scratchpads in i3wm! (video)</title><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 10:29:15 MST</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=q-l7DnDbiiU</link><description><![CDATA[<p>I talk about how to configure and customize i3wm/i3-gaps scratchpads and dropdown terminals.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">i3dropdown</guid></item><item><title>Mac Users: Don't Say T*rx on My Channel (T*rxroaches BTFO!) (video)</title><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 09:52:12 MST</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WUCuMqBlSqE</link><description><![CDATA[<p>I banned the word "torx" on my comment section to clean up some mess. Why? Watch to find out!</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">torx</guid></item><item><title>Forum is now open to public (but only YOU know!)</title><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 20:34:09 MST</pubDate><link>https://forum.lukesmith.xyz/</link><description><![CDATA[<p>I mentioned making a forum for subscribers and I've been working on it a little for the past few days. The link is at <a href="https://forum.lukesmith.xyz/">https://forum.lukesmith.xyz/</a>. I haven't posted this on YouTube or Twitter yet, but I'll go ahead and tell all of you who follow my RSS feed now.</p><p>Registration should be free and open and you should be able to post on the boards I've made so far, so feel free to, if fact, please do and go ahead and find any bugs, start dialogue etc. If everything works out, I'll probably announce it on the channel next week.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">forumrss</guid></item><item><title>LARBS preparing for release</title><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 11:55:53 MST</pubDate><link>https://larbs.xyz</link><description><![CDATA[<p>If you track my Github, you may've noticed I've been making some bigger changes to my LARBS and voidrice repositories, preparing for a re-release of LARBS with more fanfare, and more tutorial videos to go along with it (I've also updated https://larbs.xyz to HTTPS since that's a more legit concern).</p><p>There have been a lot of little improvements, and I'm hoping to have a lot of the small kinks worked out before then.</p><p>There is one thing I'd really like and don't know if it exists, and that is a kind of mutt config generator or wizard, that will automatically detect your email provider's servers and set the more annoying settings by itself. I've put some documentation up about how to configure mutt so far, but I really wish there were a way to make it easier for users.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">larbssoon</guid></item><item><title>RSS readers: You can now use HTTPS!</title><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 21:59:34 MST</pubDate><link>https://lukesmith.xyz/rss.xml</link><description><![CDATA[<p>Just as a note, you can feel free to use https://lukesmith.xyz/rss.xml as the feed URL in your feed reader as I've finally gotten SSL/HTTPS for my website.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">https</guid></item><item><title>What programs do I use?</title><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 10:51:07 MST</pubDate><link>https://lukesmith.xyz/programs.html</link><description><![CDATA[<p>I get a lot of questions about what particular programs I use for this or that. For people who don't want to troll every video of mine to find the answers, I put up a little page on my website (in link) that lists all the main stuff I use.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">programsiuse</guid></item><item><title>Dataframes in R: Columns subsets and more! (video)</title><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 09:55:20 MST</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DDzVtu24dbk</link><description><![CDATA[<p>A video on how to create modify and extract data from columns and rows in R. We talk about some of the more extensible functions that are like advanced loops in one command!</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">rdataframes</guid></item><item><title>Playing Around with Functions in R (video)</title><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 09:54:37 MST</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pgRvPNo6HaY</link><description><![CDATA[<p>A video on some of the basic functions in R, summaries, means, simple plots and more!</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">rfunctions</guid></item><item><title>Stats in R: Basics of a Beefy Calculatory (video)</title><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 16:42:06 MST</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WlCWQrKQQI4</link><description><![CDATA[<p>Here's the first in a series on R, the mathematical/statistical programming language!</p><p>Here I talk about the basics: the arithmetic, variables and the logic of vectors in R, and how R differs from typical programming languages.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">rintro</guid></item><item><title>Selecting terminal URLs with URLview (video)</title><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 21:37:49 MST</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IgzpAjFgbCw</link><description><![CDATA[<p>A brief video on URLview, which makes urls on the terminal easy to follow!]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">urlview</guid></item><item>	<title>Hard Reset on the Voidrice Repository</title>	<pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 23:13:23 MST</pubDate>	<link>https://github.com/LukeSmithxyz/voidrice</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>After several months and 70-something commits, I decided to hard reset and recommit my voidrice repository. Nothing's gone of course, there are a lot of forks and mirrors out there and I'm recommiting the files as they are today.</p>		<p>This might sound like a strange thing to do, but the repo files were getting huge (around 20MB for a repo for less than 2MB of files). I tried all the typical options, garbage collecting, even tree filtering, but couldn't reduce the size, and a small size is what I need for LARBS.</p>		<p>The main reason it got so big was when I na?vely included an enormous font system with the repo a while back to make it more accessible to Parabola users. I didn't realize how much of a pain it would be to deal with for its ease.</p>		<p>I'm planning a bigger, fuller release of LARBS, so I want to have everything clean and accessible. I may upload the old bloated repository as well on Github, maybe a "voidrice classic" and keep it as it is now, but there's a lot I've learned about system management so I like the clean feeling.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">hardreset</guid></item><item>	<title>st: suckless's Simple Terminal (video)</title>	<pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 15:40:09 MST</pubDate>	<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FJmm7wl4JUI</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>I actually got a worthwhile suckless terminal configuration going. Check out the video, and also <a href="https://github.com/LukeSmithxyz/st">my git repo</a> with my particular build.</p>		<p>It has transparency and scrollback, and a lot of helpful bindings, but also all the typical perks of st: excellent unicode compatibility and general non-bugginess.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">st</guid></item><item>	<title>An Intro to R Markdown (video)</title>	<pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 17:34:22 MST</pubDate>	<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4J5a0JWIF-0</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>A brief intro R markdown. I talk about what it does and how to compile it in vim, with a lot of its features like inline code and different output formats..</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">rmarkdownintro</guid></item><item>	<title>The Virgin LaTeX vs. the CHAD R Markdown (Video)</title>	<pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 07:50:16 MST</pubDate>	<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LWScm5WI3fo</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>I've been using R markdown as a general document formatting paradigm. It has all the perks of LaTeX but is much more manageable and with much more transparent syntax.</p>		<p>I'll be putting up another video on it soon!</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">chadrmarkdown</guid></item><item>	<title>Returning to Arizona</title>	<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 17:18:11 EST</pubDate>	<link>http://lukesmith.xyz</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>I'll be returning to Arizona and all my equipment tomorrow and hopefully will be fully cured of the flu I've had the past week. After that, I'll have more videos coming out, probably in the typical 'spree' release schedule.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">returningarizona</guid></item><item>	<title>URXVT, Basics and Configuration (VIDEO)</title>	<pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 20:43:13 EST</pubDate>	<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eaBf_yFHps8</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>A video on urxvt, including the basics, transparency with i3 and perl scripts that do all of the magic for you.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">urxvt</guid></item><item>	<title>Linguistics Videos! (Coming Whether I like it or not!)</title>	<pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 16:16:57 EST</pubDate>	<link>http://lukesmith.xyz</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>I've been rehired by the linguistics department (so I'm now working for both them and Information Sciences) and part of my assignment next semester will be making video lectures for an introductory lingusitics course.</p>		<p>One of the reasons I got this assignment is my history on YouTube, and given that, I'm going to <em>actually</em> end up making the linguistics videos I've been promising here and there.</p>		<p>The initial content will probably be very introductory, but if I get momentum in making the videos, I'll probably expand the range past what my assignment is.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">linguisticsvids</guid></item><item>	<title>Yup! Vim has a spell-checker. (VIDEO)</title>	<pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 23:38:41 EST</pubDate>	<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ez1XBUqbS68</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>A video on vim's built-in spellchecker, along with all the default bindings and possibilities, and how to use dictionaries from other languages, etc.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">vimspell</guid></item><item>	<title>Video on Net Neutrality</title>	<pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 23:54:52 MST</pubDate>	<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RgbeB79Dss0</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>Well, my check from Comcast cleared a little late, but now I've finally taken to defending Pajeet Pai's "corporate takeover of the internet". Reddit-friends on suicide watch.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">netneut</guid></item><item>	<title>sc-im: A Vim-inspired Excel replacement!</title>	<pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 09:24:05 MST</pubDate>	<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K_8_gazN7h0</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>Thanks to a viewer, Michael Novella for showing me this! It's a pretty sweet terminal spreadsheet editor with vim-like bindings. Lots of fun and a good potential replacement for LibreOffice calc.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">sc-im1</guid></item><item>	<title>ThinkPad T420 Overview</title>	<pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 16:42:34 MST</pubDate>	<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dPOLYXi2tGg</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>A brief overview of the ThinkPad T420, one of the best ThinkPads for new ThinkPad users. Sturdy, modern yet still with the classic design.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">t420</guid></item><item>	<title>"Which ThinkPad Should I Get?"</title>	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 17:58:22 MST</pubDate>	<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=La3sb5y7e-k</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>New video up on ThinkPads: the different kinds, what's popular, what's free and what's a meme.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">whichthinkpad</guid></item><item>	<title>Shortcut sync for bash, ranger and qutebrowser</title>	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 16:00:51 MST</pubDate>	<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wxlJAGiRY0o</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>See the link; I had come up with the idea for a script a while ago, but I figured it was worth redoing and making a little more robust. The idea is to keep the same aliases across qutebrowser, ranger and bash for cding to or moving/downloading files to certain directories. Check out the video or the Github repository for more info.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">shortcut2</guid></item><item>	<title>ThinkPad week is on!</title>	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 11:30:18 MST</pubDate>	<link>https://youtube.com/c/LukeSmithxyz</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>I teased doing a series on ThinkPads a couple weeks ago, but other work bogged me down. Now that classes and end of the semester administrivia are over, I'm going to have a big lump of videos coming out in the next couple days&mdash;Expect them! And it's not just ThinkPads!</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">thinkpadweek</guid></item><item>	<title>Battlestation and Apartment Tour Part II</title>	<pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 10:21:11 MST</pubDate>	<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=btYBY7jKzv4</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>My current apartment, bigger and more liveable, still no anime!</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">battle2</guid></item><item>	<title>Some channel announcements!</title>	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 22:26:24 MST</pubDate>	<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Cu-Bwr814wc</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>Bitchute, Patreon, my to-do list and much more! Check it out!</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">bitchutepattodo</guid></item><item>	<title>Make the Internet Decentralized Again!</title>	<pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 09:16:26 MST</pubDate>	<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Mtkicw97zSo</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>I'm reuploading some portions of my interview with Michael Perilloux. They'll be popping up over the rest of the week. In this segment, we talk about efforts to decentralize the internet again.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">decentralized</guid></item><item>	<title>Markdown and Pandoc for Easy Presentations...</title>	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 17:52:23 MST</pubDate>	<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dum7q6UXiCE</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>I've started to use Markdown and Pandoc to get my briefer presentations done. I strongly recommend it.</p>		<p>You can avoid the main of LibreOffice and the encumbering syntax of LaTeX/Beamer all in one.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">pandocpres</guid></item><item>	<title>On EOMA68 comuters</title>	<pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 23:14:02 MST</pubDate>	<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KvHUDHqSeuM</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>Since people have expressed interest, I did a little video on the EOMA68 to advertise the thing. You can get one that ships out next summer.</p>		<p>It's one of the few computers with actual innovation behind it, and really propose a decntralized alternative.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">eoma68on</guid></item><item>	<title>Limitations cause greatness!</title>	<pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 22:56:25 MST</pubDate>	<link>http://lukesmith.xyz</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>Alright, it's that time of year where I have to start finalizing my research projects, which means I'll be really hard-pressed for time. If that means anything, it's that I'll probably be producing <em>more</em> content than usual.</p>		<p>I'm the kind of person who when in a pinch goes the extra mile, which is good now just because I've been putting out a whole lot less content than I had wanted this semester. Good news is (a) I now have the will to do more hardcore video editing and (b) I found a way to cheat!</p>		<p>That said, I do have a lot of personal work to finish, two qualifying papers, a paper on the evolution of rationality, a corpus of Latin and probably some other stuff I've forgotten. For me that just means more limitations, and thus more motivation for output I'll probably also put out videos on my academic projects, but only as a little bonus.</p>		<p>First things first, I have a series on de-Googling coming soon, with a couple videos coming out next week.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">limitationscause</guid></item><item>	<title>On Purism Laptops</title>	<pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 23:33:07 MST</pubDate>	<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nwcOpf30SfY</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>I give my 2 cents on Purism laptops. My subscribers give their 2 cents on my now shaved head.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">purismlaptops</guid></item><item>	<title>My book library: the autistic thing I've done this weekend...</title>	<pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 17:25:11 MST</pubDate>	<link>http://lukesmith.xyz/library.html</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>I created a catalogue of all of my books for online viewing, for those who want to see them for reviews. This is also sort of a personal thing, so I can have records before my collection becomes too large.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">libraryhtml</guid></item><item>	<title>Block Ads, Tracking, Porn and whatever else with /etc/hosts</title>	<pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 09:53:58 MST</pubDate>	<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VPfpCVW7ZvM</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>New video up on creating your own firewall with /etc/hosts. An extremely easy way to limit the potentially malicious IPs your machine can connect to.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">blockadsporn</guid></item><item>	<title>Luke on Golden Age</title>	<pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 23:03:49 MST</pubDate>	<link>http://www.socialmatter.net/2017/10/23/golden-age-episode-4-software-freedom/</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>I've made an appearance on Social Matter's podcast "The Golden Age".</p>		<p>Host Michael Perilloux and I talk about software freedom, decentralization and privacy in the context of the Restoration and Neoreactionary politics.</p>		<p>Check the podcast out <a href="http://www.socialmatter.net/2017/10/23/golden-age-episode-4-software-freedom/">here</a>, and then <a href="http://socialmatter.net">SocialMatter.net</a> for even more.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">lukegoldenage</guid></item><item>	<title>10,000 subscribers!</title>	<pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 21:34:41 MST</pubDate>	<link>https://youtube.com/c/lukesmithxyz</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>A big day! I've hit 10,000 subscribers. I had no idea that anyone outside of a couple weebs on 4chan would ever actually see my channel...</p>		<p>I've come a long way. My two most popular videos (distrohopping and Apple/Mac) were both made before I had <em>100</em> subscribers, now I have a hundred times that, and both those videos are individually at over 130,000 views.</p>		<p>Looking back at my system of a year ago I can't help shaking my head either; I've improved so much and have brought a lot of people with me on this year-long (but ongoing) journey!</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">10000subs</guid></item><item>	<title>Housecleaning...</title>	<pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 02:56:51 MST</pubDate>	<link>http://lukesmith.xyz/videos.html</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>YouTube does a bad job of making older content on your channel accesible to new viewers. To partially counteract that, I've decided to put a gallery of all my YouTube videos (with thumbnails) on my website for browsing, indexed by topic.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">housecleaning</guid></item><item>	<title>The Podcast is Really Happening</title>	<pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 22:17:46 MST</pubDate>	<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8SPD35ETwuk</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>Last month, my colleague Ryan and I put out a brief introductory podcast episode, planning a series on academic affairs. We never planned out how frequent these would come out, and due to a series of life effects, it might look like it was a one time thing.</p>		<p>The feedback we got though was overwhelming and encouraging, especially given how little most of my subscribers probably cared about the issues before hand. I also had a lot of grad students in the field email glowingly. Even better was the "negative" attention we got, mostly from the Old Guard and the typical pearl-clutchers in our department. The very gall of us to serve as faces to the universal discontentment.</p>		<p>Ryan was witness to a particularly embarrassing encounter with a certaie professor absolutely apoplectic about the podcast, and recounted it to me with much gusto, variegated with uncontrollable laughter.</p>		<p>Needless to say, the more episodes are in the tubes. We're enjoying where this is going already.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">podcast</guid></item><item>	<title>Out of Town: LARBS coming soon</title>	<pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 10:32:45 EDT</pubDate>	<link>https://github.com/LukeSmithxyz/LARBS</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>I'll be out of town for the weekend on personal reason, away from my microphone, etc. So don't expect videos until Tuesday! Around then, I will probably be finishing up the LARBS (see link) which I plan on releasing then. That will make a lot of things easier for a lot of people (including me).</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">outoftownlarbs</guid></item><item>	<title>No Relation! EP1: Noam Chomsky Joins Us in Hell (Arizona)</title>	<pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 09:09:21 MST</pubDate>	<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8SPD35ETwuk</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>Starting a new podcast with my colleague Ryan Smith (no relation).</p>		<p>To christen our first episode, we discuss Noam Chosmky joining us at the University of Arizona and our general disenchantment with the generative program.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">norel1</guid></item><item>	<title>Automatic Ricing Script Part 2. (COMING SOON)</title>	<pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 21:43:33 MST</pubDate>	<link>http://lukesmith.xyz</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>I've decided to remake install scripts for Arch/Parabola since they were pretty popular last time, and I've made some pretty big changes since then.</p>		<p>Expect them sometime this week. It actually saves me a lot of time doing this, and is a lot of fun making the documentation [autism intensifies].]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">newlarbssoon</guid></item><item>	<title>Some busy work and imminent plans</title>	<pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 13:42:54 MST</pubDate>	<link>https://youtube.com/c/LukeSmithxyz</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>I have some real-world work to do this week, I have to finish writing a website and have to do some data analysis for a study, probably in R. If that ends up being interesting, I might actually just post a stream of it.</p>		<p>Otherwise, this week I'll probably put up a Battlestation video, and possibly the first of a linguistics-themed podcast.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">imminentplans</guid></item><item>	<title>Reworking the website backend</title>	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 22:06:17 MST</pubDate>	<link>http://lukesmith.xyz</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>I had some free time this afternoon, so I decided to optimize by website backend. I've started to compile my website offline with a bash script that preemptively loads the required php commands. That's a marginal economy on the server-side, but mostly just an excuse to get something done.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">websitebackend</guid></item><item>	<title>My mpd/ncmpcpp Setup</title>	<pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 23:46:23 MST</pubDate>	<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sZIEdI9TS2U</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>A brief overview of mpd and ncmpcpp and my setup with them.</p>		<p>As always, dotfiles are on Github.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">mpdncmpcpp</guid></item><item>	<title>Why I Went 2 Years with No Internet at Home</title>	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 20:03:51 MST</pubDate>	<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kiMcX3Fa2Us</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>A lot of people have asked about this on some of my videos... from 2015 to a month ago, I lived without internet at my home. This video is on why I recommend it.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">2yearwointernet</guid></item><item>	<title>Muh RSS</title>	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 20:02:05 MST</pubDate>	<link>http://lukesmith.xyz</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>I've been neglecting my RSS feed recently, considering it's a pretty robust syndication platform, I plan on remedying that.</p>		<p>This might take the form of me starting a formal blog... I haven't yet, but I already have a WP server configured and might be employing it soon.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">muhrss</guid></item><item>	<title>Video out on how I manage my website</title>	<pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 17:38:27 MST</pubDate>	<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=azkWYxyqh3Y</link>	<description><![CDATA[<p>Check out the link for details. I talk about my new paradigm for editing my website. I do plan on writing up a guide for newbies about how to start their own websites. There'll be an accompanying video too, since that's what people watch.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">managewebsite</guid></item><item>	<title>Mastering my website</title>	<pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 21:10:55 MST</pubDate>	<link>http://lukesmith.xyz</link>	<description><![CDATA[You can't see any changes on my actual website, but I've just implemented a totally new paradigm for editing and updating it.</p>		<p>I hate the internet. I like not being connected. But I pretty often have ideas for what to add to my website when I'm outside of the WWW.</p>		<p>Traditionally, I just had to remember what I wanted to change and do it when I came back into the realm of wifi, but now I'm just keeping an entire "repository" of my website on my computer here.</p>		<p>I can edit it offline, and when I get back to a reliable connection, I "push" the changes with rsync via ssh.</p>		<p>There are other huge advantages to this as well. I don't have to worry about maintaining another vimrc on the serverside, and I don't have to worry about the lag common over ssh. Plus, I have an extra little backup in case of disaster with Host Gator.</p>		<p>All in all, a good development.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">masteringwebsite</guid></item><item>	<title>Finally using Vid.Me, lol</title>	<pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 15:19:18 MST</pubDate>	<link>https://vid.me/LukeSmith</link>	<description><![CDATA[I've had some backups of earlier videos on <a href="https://vid.me/LukeSmith">Vid.Me</a> for a while, but with all the ZUCCing going on with Google and YouTube, I figure it's best to keep more recent back ups as well.		<p>Thankfully, Vid.Me always for pretty easy migration of YouTube videos, without me having to reentrer metadata, so it should be pretty easy to upkeep everything.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">vidme</guid></item><item><title>Video on calcurse, also news to come</title><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 13:44:57 MST</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hvc-pHjbhdE</link><description><![CDATA[New video out on calcurse, expect actually more content soon. I'm hoping at least two videos per week.<p>Probably today or tomorrow I'm going to be putting out a video on recent events in my life. Long story short: I was fired. I'm going to be posting a Patreon link to make up for some of the lost money, but leaving the (((university))) is a long-overdue development.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">calcurse</guid></item><item><title>i3wm video is out!</title><pubDate>Tue, 1 Aug 2017 12:49:52 MST</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-BOW61luzF4</link><description><![CDATA[Here it is, new i3 video, going over my revamping of my configs and other notes, especially for new subscribers.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">i3wmchad</guid></item><item><title>Battlestation Video (Part 1)!</title><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 14:36:10 MST</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=np5rFh0FcfU</link><description><![CDATA[New video up on my computer setup in my current appartment. I go over all the basics, but no so much the books or my other computers. I'lll do that in Part 2, which I'll release next month when I move into my new place.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">battle1</guid></item><item><title>Am I *done* configuring i3?</title><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 11:57:17 MST</pubDate><link>https://github.com/LukeSmithxyz/voidrice</link><description><![CDATA[I've push some minor changes and cleaning up to my i3 configs. Several months ago, I was always making huge changes all the time, but now I daresay that I've nearly *perfected* what I'm aiming at...<p>Changes will still come, but only trickle in as they come to me. By in large, I feel like I've converge on what I've been looking for when I started ricing.<p>Expect a video on my i3 configs soon. There will be overlap with previous vids, but I feel like this one is much more refined now.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">donei3</guid></item><item><title>Wallpapers now public</title><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 11:17:34 MST</pubDate><link>https://github.com/LukeSmithxyz/wallpapers</link><description><![CDATA[After a lot of requests, I've decided to upload all of my wallpapers into a Github repository. Check out the link for the full deal.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">wallpapers</guid></item><item><title>Corebooting/Librebooting Soon</title><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 10:09:34 MST</pubDate><link>https://paypal.me/LukeMSmith</link><description><![CDATA[I've settled back home after an abnormally long trek across country. Now that I have, I've started to accumulate the tools I'll need to begin Librebooting or Corebooting machines via Rasberry Pi.<p>Some materials are still shipping, and I'm not 100% sure how long it will take for preparation, but I'm hoping to have at least a video Corebooting my X220 up by the time our classes begin this time next month. ]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">corelibre</guid></item><item><title>How to Go Pro on YouTube!</title><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 19:59:15 MST</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g66Jhxi-gg0</link><description><![CDATA[For the 5,000 subscribers mark. I also think I'll use this as a channel greeter for non-subscribed users. Next in terms of actual content, I'm thinking of a video detailing ffmpeg and possibly a partially satirical video on distros.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">gopro5000</guid></item><item><title>5,000 subscribers mark and returning home</title><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 13:34:58 MST</pubDate><link>https://youtube.com/c/LukeSmithxyz</link><description><![CDATA[It looks like I've hit 5,000 subscribers several days ago. I haven't been able to add new videos recently, due to some summer travels and me taking a general break. I'll be returnung to Arizona within the week though, and will add some more videos then. Possibily a 5,000 subs celebration vid in the meantime...]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">5000subs</guid></item><item><title>New RSS feed</title><link>http://lukesmith.xyz/rss.xml</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 10:09:35 MST</pubDate><description><![CDATA[I'm starting this RSS feed to aggregate all my updates on different sites. I figure this is one of the more robust ways of publising content, despite the fact that only oldfags might actually use this.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">first</guid></item></channel></rss>